Hey,
hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
37.
Are you
happy for you?
morning.
All
right, start the show.
Hello everybody and welcome back. I hope
you enjoyed that lunch. I know the line
is a little long but we're all here so
I'm happy about that.
Please help me welcome our first speaker
for session two, Selius Alberti. SAS is
the SVP of research at Cognition. Please
put your hands together for Selius.
[applause]
All right, let me see if I can take this
out. Awesome.
Well, welcome to the I have the honor of
doing the first session here and I'm
very excited to talk to you guys about
scaling RL for coding agents and the
lessons from building out a research
program over the last year at Cognition.
So, I'm Silus. I'm part of the founding
team and also I lead research at
Cognition. We're known for building
Devon, the world's first AI soft
engineer and also Windsurf which uh we
acquired about a year ago. What will we
talk about today? So I wanted to tell
you a little bit of our scaling journey
of like four increasingly ambitious
training runs and in particular also how
did we pick our problems and what were
the bets we took with the scale of
compute and team that we had at the time
and also some challenges we solved along
the way like multi-turn training
parallel tool calls asynchronous RL and
entropy collapse.
So these are like the four projects that
I picked and I'm going to just like run
through the journey. Kevin 32B was um
were the humble beginnings of our of our
of our team. We were basically um
getting started. It was just like a few
interns and um I think 32 H200 GPUs and
we were trying to think okay what can we
do with this amount of compute that is
genuinely interesting and the first idea
that we had is just okay let's pick a
very targeted problem and see if we can
move something with RL on that targeted
problem. So what we picked was kernel
bench had just come out and was like a
benchmark for writing CUDA GPU kernels
uh with coding models and the idea is
basically you get a Python PyTorch
function and you have to write a CUDA
kernel that will speed up that function
and it turned out that actually worked.
So like we like implemented gpo and kind
of got it to work. I think one of the
like very interesting things we wanted
to explore at the time is what does it
look like to do multi-turn agentic
training which I think was um crazy
enough like a year ago is still pretty
novel and it's kind of cool to see also
on this graph that the multi-turn
training outperformed the single turn
training and yeah I think it was kind of
awesome we were able to basically train
like a state-of-the-art model on that
benchmark compared to like 03 which was
so at the time uh with just this like
Quen 32B like base model.
One funny anecdote um about like
training stability that I want to share
as like the one highlight from this
project is um we had a lot of like
instability problems we had to deal with
and we found this like very interesting
um instability indicator that we call
the not okay ratio. Basically the model
in its chain of thought would always
start with the word okay. This is just
like a weird quirk of this model and it
over time as the training progressed
became a little bit like crazier and
more desperate in this thinking. So here
you see some examples was like okay
amigos I need to optimize this 3D tensor
matrix multiplication and like later
through our training we be like okay
holy crap I need to get this code
optimized
and the um proxy for like instability
was we were basically measuring this
like not okay ratio and it was an early
indicator of an eventual divergence to
the training run and um it was kind of
like a very funny way of like how like
models
sometimes go wild in training.
So after this we built Swiger app and we
wanted to become a little bit more
ambitious and wanted to build like a
real useful agent that we can use in our
products and like a big thing in coding
agents is finding the right files. We
thought okay maybe we can like solve
that sub problem and make it cheaper and
faster. So the rough idea is like you
maybe have like a question about a
codebase like how does VS code
efficiently implement file watching and
then the
objective is to find the list of files
that are relevant to this question. So
pretty simple and the nice thing about
it is it's like a clean verifiable
reward because you can just do F1 score
against like the list of files
and so we went and like again trained
like an agent using RL on this task and
build our own eval that we call the code
search eval and uh it was very nice to
see that we could again train a
state-of-the-art model um on this
particular eval at the time it was like
a sonet 4.5 era
and the cool thing also was that like
these models we're able to run them like
super fast. So we're using like Sirius
chips and so mini in particular you
could run it like 3,000 tokens per
second which uh which is pretty sick.
It's also pretty magic to see the model
and so we shipped that to Windsurf
and the the most interesting thing here
is in terms of like science and what did
we figure out I mean a lot of details
obviously but the parallel tool calling.
So the the base model and most models at
the time would call like sequentially
like one tool call at a time and I think
it was around the time where like sonnet
and anthropic had just started to do
parallel tool calling. So for example
you'd see like sonnet maybe do like one
two or three tool calls at a time and we
really wanted to optimize the end to end
latency of the task which means doing as
much in parallel as possible. So sweet
grab um would sometimes run like eight
tool calls at a time and that would
really boost the internet latency. And
so here we see throughout the training
run um the reward goes up but also the
number of parallel tool calls per turn
go up a lot.
So after we grab we
said okay like now let's start building
out real like frontier coding models
that you can use for end to end tasks.
And I'm going to highlight two of these.
There's obviously more. There's 3 1.5,
but SWE 1.6 and 1.7 are the two latest
ones that we shipped earlier this year.
And
at this point, we're like, yeah, like
measuring like real coding eval like
Sweben Pro and trying to see okay, how
can we um just climb the end to end
performance on um realistic coding
problems? And so 316 we were very proud
to at the time like match opus 4.5 um on
on this benchmark.
And it's it's kind of magical to see you
like the same like fundamental
principles still apply. You just have to
obviously use more and harder data but
um throughout the training run you can
massively scale the um the soft rate. So
here you can see on like kind our
internal eval of like verifiable
software engineing tasks throughout like
one of these RL training runs we
improved from 52% to 68%.
And the other cool thing is like the
model actually learns to think for
longer. So um in the beginning it made
us thinking for on average like 4,000
thinking tokens but this roughly doubled
throughout the training run.
And it really also taught us like what
does it actually mean to have stable
training like a good algorithm because
it wasn't obviously as easy as just like
taking the data and like running the
model. There are all kinds of collapses
and stability issues. And so here you
can see um two of these. And basically
what would happen is like as we were
like trying to like tune the algorithm
maybe after like 200 steps the model
would collapse and then we would like
diagnose the problem figure out like
okay what is the root cause and then
after we uh restart it's kind of
interesting to see how this almost like
follows the exact same trajectory but
then at the point of collapse now it's
like more stable and kind of keep going.
So with each algorithmic improvement, we
could improve the training horizon from
like 200 steps to 300 steps and like
push it further.
Another thing that I think was kind of
novel for us in this uh project was
asynchronous RL and how do we maximize
the throughput of these like longer and
longer rollouts. And basically the
fundamental idea is that you um separate
your trainer and your rollouts
and the rollouts just send um additional
batches of groups to the um data buffer
and the trainer just like slurps up the
data buffer as it gets full and then
when it has done a training step it will
send an weight update to the rollouts.
And I'm going to come back to this a
little bit later when we talk about 317
as well. Um, and so one downside of a
synchronous RL is that your like
training policy, your inference policy
can diverge, right? So you might receive
a batch of data that is from like an
inference policy is like a couple steps
old. And this is what we call staleness.
So the number of steps that your
inference policy is behind the training
policy
and um interestingly
it all comes full circle because the
better you can improve the training
stability of your algorithm the more
staleness you can tolerate. So
especially as we were getting started we
were basically almost
incapable of having high stailness but
over time we were able to push this. So
here you see like two training runs um
that we compare and the black training
run can tolerate a much higher average
stallness and what this gives us is the
ability to just fully utilize our
inference engines. So a better algorithm
allows us to achieve full comput
utilization
and this leads us to SU 1.7 our latest
model and here you can see um these days
you know you no longer do a 1D bar chart
you do these like 2D costs versus uh
performance charts and what I think it's
worth calling out here is the model does
particularly well for its size class so
The base model that we trained on in
this case was Kimmy K2.7 which you see
um down there and obviously this
composer 2.5 which is also based in
Kimmy and GLM 5.2 which is roughly the
similar size and for its size class it
is um quite um impressively high and
competing at the level of many much
bigger models while being much cheaper.
And what were the things that it took?
So I think especially as you try to
squeeze the most out of these smaller
model I mean obviously one trillion
parameters is still big but it's maybe
not a multi- trillion parameter model as
some of the frontier models. Um we were
hearing a lot of chatter about like like
RL is like hitting a plateau and now
it's like all about pre-training but we
wanted to see okay can we push this a
little bit further. At this point we're
bottlenecked by entropy collapse. So
obviously the juice of your RL
improvements is do you have diversity in
your group and do you have like
discovery of new behaviors
and this is all measurable by what we
call entropy. And so what you usually
see throughout a training run is that
entropy goes down over time and
eventually um entropy is kind like
collapsed and then you've hit the
ceiling of your RL training run. And we
were really battling with this because
you know we just couldn't improve the
model anymore.
But uh the good news is like you know if
you keep tuning your other recipe and
you should read our technical report for
a lot of the details we were able to get
a recipe that had was almost like an
imperceptible decline in entropy. I
think it would still decline over time
but it's like a much uh flatter slope.
And so the nice thing is yeah we were
able to just push the performance much
more.
Another cool thing is um how we were
training across three continents. So
obviously we want to scale up [snorts]
the compute more and more and it's just
like genuinely hard these days to like
find big contiguous training clusters
and especially on like the timelines
that you eat like maybe you can like
order them like a year in advance but um
so so like what we found much easier is
to like find smaller [snorts] slices of
compute here and there like maybe like
like a small cluster here another
cluster there and the um end result of
this was like a training run that was
operating across four countries and
three continents including Australia,
Malaysia, Canada and the US.
And the reason why this um why I was
saying earlier we're going to come back
to async RL is the only reason why this
is possible is because of async RL and
the rough like layout of this training
run is that we basically have a training
cluster which in this case was in the US
and then we have a lot of rollout
clusters that are like scattered across
the world and the way these this whole
like system speaks to each other is that
the infrance Inference clusters send the
training batches to the training cluster
and then the training cluster sends
weight updates to the um inference
clusters and the whole reason why we can
do this over the whole globe is because
actually these the information that
needs to be transmitted is pretty sparse
[snorts] in RL like database are pretty
sparse and then also the training
batches are just like tokens
and with that um I'll wrap up with uh
maybe like recapping what Our philosophy
with a lot of this has been which is
like we are actually not really like our
belief is it doesn't really take complex
things and like fancy ideas a lot of
progress and research is just executing
the simple things of scare and that I'll
say uh thank you so much for having me
and I'll hand it back to
thank you so much Silus
that was amazing I this is not an
endorsement necessarily But I do use
Devon in cognition often. So thank you
for your work.
All righty. Next up we have Oh, thank
you. We have Duvatra. Duru Batra is the
chief scientist and co-founder of URI.
So please put your hands together for
Duv.
[applause]
Okay. Um, thank you for having me. Um,
I'm Duv. I'm the chief scientist of
Ytori and one of the co-founders. Um,
unlike a regular talk where I just give
you a spiel about our company, I want to
talk about something, you know, fairly
different. Um, I want to talk to you
about a specific argument and a
counterargument. And the specific
argument is that there's a popular
narrative online that you hear, which is
that uh AI agents will be the primary
drivers of action on the web, not
humans. Um that they will be booking
meetings for us, booking appointments
for us, buying things for us, securing
information for us, and so on. Okay,
that's the claim. Step number two, when
you ask people who make that claim, how
the answer usually is, well, the web
will be agentified. it will be made
agent friendly. Okay. Uh when you ask
how uh the response to that is that with
APIs that my agents and your agents and
our enterprise agents will call through
14 different standards um MCP, web MCP,
you know, payment protocols and so on.
And today I just want to make a very
specific argument that the first two
steps are right, the third step is
wrong. This argument does not work and I
will give you a counter uh argument for
that. Um, so that's my claim for this
talk is that computer use agents, which
are agents that operate computers and
browsers like a human by looking at the
screen and pressing buttons will
identify the the web and more
specifically the long tail of the web
and not APIs. Your websites, the long
tail of websites will not have APIs
available. Um and in order to uh
demonstrate that viscerally, let's begin
with the example that most people
commonly show um in in this literature
which is a consumer or a developer is
sitting there at their iPhone asking you
know find me this flight and you imagine
a a behind the scenes a browser use
agent or a computer use agent operating
a browser going to flights.google.com
clicking those buttons like a human
does. This is an extremely common demo
in this literature and it is ludicrously
funny because why would you possibly do
this? There are API services that are
aggregators. It's a database. You can
send in a structured query, get a
structured query back. Why would you
possibly click buttons to do this? Um my
claim is that let's generalize this. Um,
let's say instead of that question, I
ask you, I'm planning an evening uh
gathering with my friends. And what I
want to know is I will point you to a
restaurant and ask you, are there any
gluten-free items on this restaurant's
menu? And what people imagine is that at
some point uh there will be myfrest
restaurant.commen
as a endpoint that you can just curl and
ask a natural language query or filter
it by saying give me the gluten-free um
menu items on your menu. Um and for
people who think that either this is
reality or this is what's coming, I
would like to show to you what actual
restaurant websites look like. Um uh
I'll have my slides later online. Today
I'll just show you a couple of easy,
medium, hard mode of what these things
look like. When you go to the easy mode,
people imagine restaurants like this
where there is some text you can read.
In medium mode, you get PDFs which are
menu items. In hard mode, you get a
gallery of individual scans of pages of
menus and that's just stuck together,
pixelated, not even OCRD. And so these
are the people. They are small business
owners. They exist somewhere. There's
about 200,000
small business owners in a single let's
say country in in Europe that maintain
their own websites. And what you are
imagining is that tomorrow or in the
next 5 years they will all be
revolutionarized so that there are
gateways for your agents to to pull. Um
my claim here is this is not coming.
Like the the cavalry that we're waiting
for is not coming. The web is extremely
longtailed. Uh those individual websites
may be of limited value but the tail
cumulatively has a lot lot of value and
infrastructure changes slowly. Um
and at this point usually the response
is okay fine. Uh let's just read the
code. We have coding agents. Uh let's
read the HTML. Uh we can do this. Um,
and I'd like to walk you through another
example why that's a bad argument, why
that cannot be done. Um, let's say you
want to know on a e-commerce website, is
this 24mm Osmium cube in stock or out of
stock? It's a it's a really simple
query. The there's a product page and
you just have to answer is this in stock
or out of stock. You scroll down and you
know there's a quantity button that you
that you drop down. That selector tells
you and me with eyeballs who can see
pixels uh that three of those items are
sold out. They're not available. One of
those items is available. However, when
you send your agents to read the HTML
for this for this page, what you see is
that the selector says nothing about the
quantities. The HTML actually has
selectors that have descriptors for the
items, but nothing about the quantity.
Why? Well, so everybody who understands
JavaScript and web technology at this
point is shaking their head. You idiots,
you thought this would happen. Um,
behind the scenes there is a a query
that is made that when the page loads
gets a JSON object or a dictionary that
is filled with with at that moment what
does that store have and it has
quantities and stock uh listed there.
And then when you click the drop down
there is a different part of code that
renders whether it should show up as
grayed out or it should show up as as
color. Um and this is because you know
we see this but behind the scenes a
browser is a rendering engine. For
people who have worked in video game
technology the analogy made that you
should be making is a browser really is
a renderer. Like there's a there's you
know assets underneath there's code
ultimately pixels are produced. And so
the claim is that the web was built for
human eyeballs. That is the source of
the truth. And so machines will need to
operate with vision. Um we at UTI wrote
a blog about this called the bitter
lesson for web agents that if you do not
look at the pixels, you get stuck
feature engineering to reach the long
tail of the web. Um,
uh,
whoever's handling the laptop, could you
take that bit out? Want to make a
presentation like this? Uh, that's
taking half my slide away. Um,
but okay. Uh, we built a model. It's
called, if the full slide was there,
it's called navigator. It's a pixels
toactions model that looks at a screen
like a human would and predicts uh,
actions to be
okay. this. Yes, please.
>> Yes, there's an X. No, no, no. Don't
create a [laughter]
>> Okay, it is free. At this point, I do
want my computer use agent operating
that computer.
>> Yes.
If if I could just get back to the
slides.
Look, man, APIs are not arriving, but my
computer use agent is arriving. It'll
[laughter] do it'll do a better job than
this.
Oh, thank you. And full screen button.
Yes,
perfect. and I will I will make my way
there. Thank you. Appreciate it.
Okay.
So, this is what we build at. It's a
model called navigator. Takes as input a
screenshot of the browser, produces as
output a human-like action like
clicking, typing, scrolling on a
browser. uh the kind of thing that was
just happening here with a human telling
a another human what to do and the other
human producing button clicks. Imagine
if the other human was a machine in this
case. Um and so you know you could do
things like I tell you about a website
uh it's it's a e-commerce website and I
just ask you I have a promo code does it
work or not? There's no API for that.
the the the store account will never
give you that API. And so this machine
will go open that browser, you know, go
through a mock checkout flow, apply the
promo code, look at the price, did it go
down or not, and we'll send you a
structured object saying yes, this promo
code works and actually, you know, the
price went down by 22% or whatever. Um,
and there is your API of the web. Um
while I do claim that machines will need
to operate with vision um they will not
be limited to human ways. Um so you do
have to be superhuman and on uh on this
screen what I'm showing is a form
filling task where what the what the
model does on the right is directly read
the and write JavaScript. So the model
has an action called execute JavaScript.
It writes custom code and it fills out a
bunch of fields uh simultaneously. So it
does not have to be limited to button
clicks. At this point of time you might
ask well are computer use models good
enough. Um and there is a narrative
online that computer use amongst all
capabilities is stuck. Somehow coding
agents are making a bunch of progress
and computer use agents have not. And
it's not true. That's not what the the
reality is telling us. Benchmarks after
benchmarks are falling. This is a
benchmark that is run by an academic
group um at Ohio State. Over the last
couple of years, the benchmark has
essentially gotten saturated. Uh most
recently um as of like a month ago,
where the accuracies are now sitting at
97% so the benchmark is essentially done
and we'll have to create new ones. At
this point, the last argument that
stands is people ask well are computer
aren't computer use models slow and
expensive and there as well my answer
would be no. Specialized models are
getting quite good if you are using a
frontier model. So on this slide I'm
comparing to Opus 4.7 and GPD 5.5. Yes,
those are often slow. Every action takes
you about you know 10 seconds in GPD uh
5.5's case and you know the whole task
takes you to $230 on some on some data
set. Uh the model we train is
significantly smaller therefore just as
accurate but slightly faster.
So um that was the entire argument. I
think the web is uh you know machines
are going to be the drivers of action on
the web. Uh we've had 30 years of web
for human consumption that is changing
but the how matters. I think the way we
will have this API where you could pull
any website and describe any task in
natural language is by having a sea of
agents that are operating browsers in
the background. And that's that's it.
Thank you.
Thank you, Drew. So, I mean, if I've
learned anything today is that someone
needs to go build a slides agent. We
need that ASAP.
Um, all right. Please help me welcome
our next presenter. Our next presenter
is Shamir Abdul Aziz. He is a principal
product manager at Microsoft. Please put
your hands together for Shamir.
>> Good afternoon, everyone. All right.
I've been interested with five minutes
to distill what we have learned at
Microsoft building agents and running
them uh in the last two years. So let me
try uh apparently the first lesson is uh
in agentic AI compression is a thing. So
I'll try and honor the five minutes. So
what I'm going to talk about today is a
world where agents operate and humans
govern. And for decades now, uh, humans
have been operating using software
systems like we build dashboards and
metrics and alerts and automation and
very recently started using C-pilot to
get your job done, but it's still using
humans to do that, right? And how do we
flip it? So the story that I'm going to
narrate today is how we flipped it at
Microsoft and the learnings you can take
home.
All right. If I if I had one slide to
compress all of that we learned in the
last couple of years, it is this. So the
first thing I want to talk about is zero
ops, right? Uh the destination. And this
is not about removing humans from
operations. It's about removing the
operations from humans. And you'll see
in the later slides what I mean by that.
Uh and models are swappable. You can
change models. Models are getting better
each day. But your context, your
governance and your tools are not. And
so invest on that. Um to make an agent
useful, uh the models alone cannot
provide you the intelligence. You need
to be able to govern it and control it
and you have to give it the right
context. And governance is a key piece
of all of this. Uh uh enterprises love
intelligence that you they get out of
it. But if they cannot control the
intelligence, then you're not going to
earn their trust. And speaking about
trust, um you need to be able to have
verifiable metrics that will allow you
to validate what the agent has done and
what the outcomes are. And so with that,
let me get into the uh the crux of the
slides. So what is zero ops? Zero ops is
a vision where agents will start doing
more operations, take out the mundane
work out of humans and you uh bump up
the humans to do much more impactful
work, innovation or governance and
things like that. And it's it's a
destination and so there's going to be a
journey. So you're going to do crawl,
walk, run and fly. And fly is not just
execution. It's not that agent is doing
something. You allow the agent to do
something. validate its outcome and
provide the outcome for the humans to
validate. To give you an example, if an
agent is fixing a regression in an API
because the performance went slow. So,
it goes ahead and creates a PR. That's
easy. It created a PR. Fine. But what's
better is when the agent not just
creates a PR, deploys the PR in a test
environment, validates the outcome and
confirms the regression is gone away and
the performance is back to normal.
Right? And that is what we uh call
outcome based engineering where humans
not reviewing every diff, they're
reviewing the outcome.
Like I said, context is everything. Uh
models are not the moat. What is your
moat? The moat is your source code, your
pro uh production telemetry, your
institutional knowledge and uh the
skills and tools you provide the system.
Once you do this, the agents can be
automated and get things done for you.
Agents uh uh need to be trusted and to
be able to trust agents enterprise needs
to be able to audit, control, evaluate,
roll back with confidence and prove with
evidence what the agent did was the
right thing that it had to do. Right? So
without this enterprise are not going to
go and do it. I see one minute up. So uh
finally the last two slides you need
permissions metrics are important way to
validate the outcome and unless you see
permissions you're not going to allow
let see enterprises deploy agents at
scale and talking about scale this is
the story of Microsoft implementing
Azure S sur agent you don't have to
build this ground up you get all of this
baked into the product and so whatever I
talked about is built into the product
and we have deployed more than 5,000
agents uh at enterprise level at
Microsoft some of the largest
engineering teams are using this product
today and you can see in the numbers
there 1.5 millions incidents processed
and almost 220,000 incidents automated
so when context governance and metrics
come together that's when you achieve
zero ops with that I conclude my session
>> [applause]
>> Thank you Shamir. I know it's not easy
to go in five minutes but that was
really really good. All right please
help me welcome our next presenter
Krishna Kumar Shama. Krishna Kumar
Sharma is the CEO at Omaki Omakai. Uh
Krishna if you can make there we go
there.
Please put your hands together for
Krishna.
Let's see.
Okay.
I hope you all are enjoying the
sessions. Actually learned quite a lot
myself by listening to other speakers
here.
If someone is building a slide agent,
I'm happy to collaborate with you.
Okay, awesome. So, here we go. So, hi
folks. Today I'm going to speak about
agentic coding the boring way. And this
talk will focus on legacy systems the
enterprises. And while I say the boring
way, if you are someone who wants to
build systems and solutions which are
scalable, which are secure, which are
reliable, then maybe you will find this
talk very interesting. So why I might be
the right person to speak about this
topic. So I am Krishna. Uh I used to be
head of AI at Amazon Germany. I have
built large scale AI systems. I have
brought billions in dollars in revenue
impact for Amazon. As I've worked in
robotics AI as well, I decided to start
my own startup.
And in Omukai, I'm building an physical
AI operating system. We are turning
voice into autonomous missions for
robots and drones. While today I will
not be speaking about what we are doing
in Omoai. I will be talking about how I
am building and we'll be touching on the
coding part. how the engineering teams
in Omukai are actually trying to solve
uh some problems and maybe some things
which I'm going to say here will be
super controversial. So uh I look
forward to that and look forward to your
uh feedback. So one thing about Omokai,
we are like very AI native. We custom we
use our own models which are uh
fine-tuned and we use AI to generate
data. uh we do have like seven human
employees but more than 10 AI employees.
So whatever I'm saying might be still
quite relevant to you. So first thing
first why uh I'm talking so much about
legacy environment. I believe that we
are having an agentic hangover because
as per research published by Gartner as
you can see using more AI does not leads
to more productivity. It just leads to
you making anthropic and open air richer
and maybe you want to become rich
yourself, right? So uh if you are using
AI unbounded without proper constraints,
maybe you are not using AI correctly and
what I have witnessed is that there is a
lot of chaos, there is lot of noise,
there is lot of hype around how agentic
system should be building and first of
all I would like to touch base upon some
myths. So example um you might have
heard about agent swamps like using
hundreds of um agents to solve a
problem. This only leads to lot of cost
and lots of errors. Second thing which
is quite popular these days is like loop
engineering or loop within loop as I
have seen some people doing. This also
will lead to a lot more cost uh than
what you would uh want to look at. And
if you are of an opinion that AI will
get very cheap in future and it these
things the cost will not matter then I
have one more data point as for another
research done on using AI for code
generation. If you use AI unc in
uncontrolled way, you end up creating
lot more errors and lot more persistent
errors in your production databases and
maybe you would not want to do that and
then apart from all that there is a lot
of u hidden cost of using AI without
control from verification to the
security loopholes to debugging and in
in the end the cognitive dep
burnout. I don't know how many of you
how many of you have experienced it but
this is a real thing because if you use
AI too much you end up losing a lot of
context. So how we can solve this
problem and uh oh yeah before we go to
the problem this is one guy screaming at
the internet because he's tired of um
this opensource repository uh creating
lot of AI slope so we don't want to do
that right so let's get into some
solution let's get let's bring some
discipline so I as I've worked in Amazon
uh what I have learned is that
frameworks and mechanisms they help you
a lot in building reliable and scalable
systems And today I would be speaking
about um mechanism which I developed at
Amazon for agentic coding. We did this
back in 2025. It's called D3 framework
for agentic coding. It is quite
straightforward. There are like three
phases. So first phase is discover where
you create a research artifact. This
research artifact contains all
information about your repository but
also upstream and downstream uh
dependencies. Then based upon this
research document you create a plan like
very well definfined plan and this plan
has um the task created like subtask
created and then this information goes
into the deliver phase where an AI takes
all this information and uh solves the
problem and another thing is that I
believe that at this point you cannot
trust AI fully. So we should have some
sort of human sign off and you should
use multiple different models not from
like same family but different companies
while you are solving the problem. Last
thing I would like to say is that uh you
should not use too many agents try to
use maybe four and well definfined uh
agents. Last thing before um if one
thing you want to take from this session
that is stop token maxing and start ROI
maxing and if you would like to connect
with me let's connect over LinkedIn. I
am doing a lot of work on robotics and
drones as well. So looking forward to
connecting with you. Thank you so much.
>> That was awesome.
That was awesome. All righty. Next up,
we have a workshop by Fetcher. So,
please help me welcome Urieli
to the stage.
More, more, more. There we go.
>> Thank you.
So, thank you everyone for joining this
session.
I'm Urieli. As said, I'm the chief AI
officer and co-founder at Fetcher. A few
words about myself before we begin.
Um, so I've been building decision
making systems, quantitative decision-
making systems for more than three
decades now.
And uh some of these decision-m systems
were based on algorithmic trading uh
high frequency trading as I was head of
AI division in algorithmic trading
company
and my academic background is a PhD in
computational neuroscience
and some of the slides hopefully when
the slides show up that you'll see are
based on biology techology and
computational neuroscience.
Um
generally we at fetcher deploy decision
making systems in various enterprises
and um today I will uh discuss some of
the concepts behind these decision-
making systems. The decision- making
systems are naturally quantitative and
there are many lessons that can be
learned from biology, from evolution
um that are inspiring and have inspired
the architecture before behind our
decision- making systems.
So, let's see.
the house.
>> Okay.
Yeah. So um initially for more than a
decade I
was in a trading firm making algorithmic
trading
and many of the concepts behind trading
to today almost 20% 90% of the volume in
NASDAQ and other capital markets is
based on algorithmics and back then uh
in the trading firm I was uh in these
decisions were based on models that are
predicting the future market dynamics in
NASDAQ and in New York Stock Exchange
and other markets. And then um you all
probably know that most of the capital
markets got into a situation where they
are very based on speed and I was always
interested in making the right decision
not based on speed but based on being
smart and that's why we turned into
other markets that are not capital
markets to make the decisions.
Clicker doesn't work.
Okay.
Okay, clicker skill still still doesn't
work but I will talk about the next
slide. So
um there are certain principles as I
said that have uh
designed uh our decision-m systems and
some of them are based on biology.
And speaking of biology, we have this
biological decision-making systems uh
our human brains and they have evolved
over hundreds of millions of years and
have produced certain regions that are
specialized in processing different
kinds of data from the natural worlds
and solving different kinds of problems.
We for processing for example uh visual
data we have
uh our uh visual cortex for planning we
have the prefrontal cortex and we have
different regions for processing sound
and taste and touch and so on. But
what's important is not the exact
location the precise location of each of
these regions. What's important is that
it shows that the architecture of such a
decision making system needs to reflect
the complexity and the structure of the
environment in which the decisions are
made.
Now let's compare that with what happens
in agentic workflows that are making
decisions in
uh the business arena. These workflows
are always the
in their center they have a language
model. There are some layers that take
care of K or they that take care of
harnessing or maybe some visual models
too but at their core these systems are
based on language models. These language
models are extremely powerful
but still
they are trained primarily to generate
text and process text. And that raises
the question
of are these language models um that
these language centric architectures
are they sufficient for making business
decision
because
there is a correlation between what
happens in the natural world and the
structure of the brain that makes
decisions in the natural
There are some
first class citizens in the natural
world of images of sound of movement
that are projected into the structure of
the decision making system. The brain in
that natural world but we don't see that
correlation in the business world. The
brain the the central system in the
agentic workflows is based on language.
But the main concepts in the business
world are concepts like price, like
supply, like demand. And these concepts
are not the first class citizens in this
decision-making system. That's why we in
Fetcher we believe that language models
are not enough for making quantitative
decisions.
for making such decisions. Um s the
decision- making systems needs to be
able to really sense the market to have
the market sensation to be able to
forecast the future market dynamics to
be able to simulate various scenarios
and among these scenarios to to choose
and optimize the best decisions
and act on them. It needs to
quantitatively
be able to evaluate the rewards of every
such decision. Of course, language
models and harnessing layers are
essential here,
but the optimal decisions are dependent
on tools that needs to be trained
directly on the dynamics of the business
environment.
That's why we in Fcher while most of the
AI community was focused on
language models, we were building during
the recent years our market models.
These market models are not trained
solely on text. They are trained on the
market dynamics and they are the core of
the systems that in various enterprises
today enable autonomous quantitative
decisions. The market models can be
compared to other deep learning models
because all of these types of models are
based on same techniques, same
layers, types of layers of deep learning
and neural networks.
But there's a tweak here where while the
language models are trained on text and
visual models are trained on images or
video,
uh our market models are quite similar
to large world models. While large world
models are trained on data or simulative
data of the physical environment, the
market models are based on data of the
market environment. So looking deeper
into that the the basic concept of uh
language models are the tokens that are
inputed into the model and outputed from
the model.
And the basic concept behind the visual
models are threedimensional tensors of
having height of image, width of image
and color depth of image.
And in each combination of these tensor
we have these visual pixels that
represent the intensity
of the light in that combination. In
market model uh we are talking about a
much more multi-dimensional
uh structure. Um some of the dimensions
here represent the time of a
transaction, time of a delivery of the
transaction,
uh attributes of the product, attributes
of the uh customer class and so on. And
each in each such combination we have
these voxels that are not visual voxels
but probabilistic ones representing the
probability of certain event to occur.
for example, event of a transaction of a
cancellation or a competitor repricing.
And these market models are p are only
part of the tools that are available for
the agentic workflow in order to make
the actual decision. That workflow
starts with consolidation of data from
various sources in order to feed the
market model.
The market model is then once trained it
is it can
predict the future market dynamics.
These predictions are used then to
simulate various scenarios into the
future and one of the scenarios is
chosen in order to inject the right
decision at every point
into the um enterprise systems.
Let's start with the for example um
consolidation of data. Data in that
sense would be pro proprietary data of
the enterprise for example it's
historical transactions and that data
can be enriched from
external world by for for example
anything that can be predictive
regarding the market like events
um capital markets data weather any type
of information can be consolidated here
in order to feed the market model. Now
the market model is also a deep learning
system as I said before and that enables
us to peak into that brain of market
model just like language systems and try
to understand what's going on what does
it pay attention to because it includes
also attentional layers. For example,
here that's a case where we took one of
these market models
uh for one of our customers
and uh
in in the data we knew that there is a
new competitor joining the market mid
year and we try to understand how much
attention does that entrance of a new
competitor
cause. Uh the new competitor here is
represented in yellow. And the market
model was uh quite smart based on the
attribute of this new competitor and the
attributes of the other competitors to
red to redistribute its attention among
the different competitors
according to their importance.
Now that's uh what relates to the
uh peing into the brain of the market
model. But what's maybe more important
is the output of the market model.
Because as I said the market model
output is multi-dimensional. It has many
dimensions and we the engineers in
fetcher we like to visualize these
dimensions as humans. Now, as humans, we
can visualize maybe two or three
dimensions or maybe four, as we'll see
in a moment. Um, and in order to make
that visualization, we need to slice
that multi-dimensional cube at a certain
point. For example,
um, fix or attribute as fixed some of
the dimensions. For example, set a very
specific product, very specific type of
customer,
um specific time of transaction, time of
delivery, and play only with
only with
um
a few dimensions like the own price,
meaning the price that we might give our
product on the x-axis here. the price
that our competitor might choose to
price his alternative product, his
competing product on the y-axis.
And we in that case we are looking at
the expected demand the way the market
model sees it. [snorts] And the market
model the beauty here is that these
outputs are automatically generated. The
market model knows exactly how to
quantify the expected demand based on
the historical data. And um as you can
see here, it all makes sense uh because
the blue areas are the areas where the
market model thinks the expected demand
is going to be quite low. These areas
are the areas where our price is higher
or significantly higher compared to the
competitors. Uh the red areas are areas
where it expects high demand. These are
the opposite cases. And the market model
also sees that equilibrium line between
the different types of um
between us and the competitor. That's
where the the public the the people that
are uh buying the products don't really
care about that difference.
And uh another nice thing here is that
if we slice that cube in different
locations, we can understand what does
the market modal think of the
difference. For example, between these
two markets where the market model tells
us that it thinks the right market is a
market where the competition has very
low impact compared to the left case or
a market where the equilibrium line
moves a little. In that case, it moves
to the right by 50 price units, which
means that
um the perceived value of our product in
that market is higher compared to the
competition.
uh or here we can see a case where uh
the market model thinks that the right
market is much more competitive because
it's contrast is higher and every cent
matters when making the pricing actions.
We can also try to see how does this um
surface of demand change over time. For
example, we have pulled this case to see
how does this uh demand surface change
over time in correlation to the fuel
prices that's related to airline uh
pricing demand surface. And we can see
that when the fuel prices rised up
around April this year, the demand was
impacted accordingly
based on the predictions of the market
model.
Now once the uh these predictions are
available they can be used using
simulation to evaluate what is the
expected reward. So for every pricing
policy we can simulate using a digital
twin of the business arena what would be
the reward. For example, let's take this
case
which is a very simplified case where we
treat [snorts] the business uh the
decision policy as a two parameters
policy based on decision one and
decision two and in every combination of
such decisions we expect a certain
reward for example a certain revenue
and the nice thing here is that these
predictions s can be done continuously
and reflect the the data that flows in
into the market model. And that that
flowing in in of data into the market
model reflects the the change in the
reward landscape because reality change
all the time. And we as a business want
always to be at the peak of the hill.
And when the reality changes,
these systems know how to move their
decision policy according to what
happens in reality. So in some cases,
you you can see we we call these hills
there are several hidden hills under
here. A each one of these hills is
called in in our sense a decision-m
regime. And in some cases something
changing the reality and such a systems
know that it needs to move from regime A
to regime B because the hill of regime B
is much higher in that reward landscape.
Now the outcomes of these uh systems
can be tested in AB testing.
Uh whenever we deploy our system, we
deploy it on a subset of markets
and that we uh we see as a target group
and we con we compare the results of
that subset to an other correlated group
which is the control group. And
repeatedly in every case we see that
these quantitative decision-making
systems are showing s statistically
significant
results of revenue uplift as in here
where the distribution of revenue is
shifted to the right significantly in
about 7% on average.
Now what I've shown today are a set of
tools
uh that uh are essential uh tools for
bridging uh the transitioning of the
decision- making industry
from
a practices that are based on general
harness engineering
to practices that are more
enterprisegrade
uh truly reliable
agent operations.
And in the next workshop,
Hadar Sharvit from Fetcher who is the VP
of large market model and machine
learning in Fetcher will dive into the
uh details of these tools that I
presented today. Thank you very much.
Hey everyone.
Somebody wants to guess how much time
I'm going to wait for the slides. Maybe
let's do
couple minutes.
So you're saying if a question whether
we'll be able to predict outcomes of
soccer games or
Yeah. So, we're actually going to talk
about that specifically and we're going
to see how um when you delegate agentic
workflows to forecasting backbones that
are able to forecast um reliably, then
some nice things happen. But that's a
good question.
Um all right. So, hello everyone. My
name is Hadar uh former director of deep
learning at Fetcher and now entering VP
of the market model which is Fetcher's
proprietary model for decision- making
using artificial intelligence. In this
session, I'm going to go through the
process of justifying the statement that
is written here down below. Essentially
why we believe that large language model
might struggle with highstake uh
quantitative decisions and how by
delegating some of the decision to
guaranteed tools that have the ability
to understand the market and make
reliable decisions we can kind of
combine the two tools and and kind of
see how they benefit from one another.
So in this workshop we're going to talk
talk about the architecting aspects of
what we call uh those quantitative
decision agents. We're going to dive uh
deep. So, straighten up and prepare for
for the following uh 40 something uh
minutes. Let's talk about how business
decisions are uh are being made. So, you
know, all of us have been tackled or
have been asked uh a business question
in their history or even on a day-to-day
basis, right? An airline might ask
itself, how should I price a business
class seat uh now, in a week from now,
in six months, in 12 months from now? or
a sales team might ponder how they want
to how big of a discount they want to
provide for their clients in order to
make meaningful uh revenue um um
indication. And the examples are pretty
obvious. They're all around us. And we
want to kind of say that in many cases
in order to come up with a meaningful
answer, you want to pair up two
capabilities. One of them is a
predictor, a forecaster that tells us
how a market is going to move or how the
business objective is going to move into
the future based on some signals that we
care for. And the other is an
optimization process that would reliably
could be consume the predictions of this
forecaster to say a meaningful uh policy
of of how to how to um what actions to
apply. So an airline might say that
based on its forecasting capability
holiday season would be uh uh is is is
soon to end and therefore demand
prediction as far as they understand
that will surely fall and therefore
their decision would be to decrease the
prices on that specific seat in that
specific market and obviously there are
many examples. Now I'm going to talk
about the mathematics behind those two
capabilities starting from the
forecasting. uh what you can see here uh
is a mathematical repres representation
of what we call or what the industry
calls a point forecast. In the diagram
that below the equation that I will
outline in in words, you can see that
the target that we have here is to
predict into the future from some point
in time denoted by lower script t uh
whatever signal we are interested in. In
the following uh slides, I'm going to
follow the structure of we want to
predict demand or mark the market
dynamics as outlined for the most part
by demand and other properties and we're
going to use information we know from
the past and some information from the
future in order to make this for
forecast accurate. So in this setup um
any forecaster usually a deep neural
network parameterized in in some learned
parameters data is consumed the known
past information in this case the known
uh demand the known uh in in an airline
industry or any industry that has
products perishable products that are
intended to sell. What was the demand?
What was the distribution of demand in
the past? uh but not only that there are
some features that in the industry might
be referred as coariantss or exogenous
variables. Some of them are known to the
past like for a specific product what
was the uh uh representation of the
product what was its associated price
but also there are more information like
static information that represents
products themselves um ids uh some some
uh properties that are invariant
[clears throat] in time and other
information that is also known to the
future expected holiday maybe you know
how's the weather is going to look like
in a high confidence in the near future
or also you kind of information that is
time related like what day of the week
it's going to be uh what uh what's going
to be information about the time right
so everything is being consumed by
whatever forecaster you'd like I'm going
to follow an example of a deep learning
architecture that essentially predict
from pointy up to what we refer to as
the horizon how is the signal that we
care for is going to look like now
alternatively the point forecast is
immediately translated to a distribution
because some cases Businesses want to
know something about uncertainty. They
want to think about the forecast in
means of confidence. And therefore, when
you change the uh neural network uh
output head, you can essentially say
we're not going to predict a forecast.
demand was seven seats for that specific
uh business class cabin, but rather
there's some distribution that could be
either parameterized by learning for
example a multi-dimension um neural
distribution or you could describe
uncertainty by means of quantiles. We
will soon see some examples.
Now this is the first part and we also
talked about an optimization process. An
optimization process essentially takes
the pre-trained forecaster and says in
this example um the the uh probabilistic
forecast and says given that we have
some reward or some mechanism that the
business wants to either maximize or
minimize denoted by u given some context
denoted by s those are the pass
information the price signals the static
information that we have and a set of
feasible actions that could be how to
set the price for a specific product,
how many inventory to allocate. We want
to maximize some objective that is
essentially says let's let's see how our
signal how demand is going to be looking
like in the past whatever the horizon
might be. See what the expectation is
and kind of find an action within the
feasible action set that kind of
maximizes um what we want to to achieve.
Right? This could be for example price
as an action to maximize revenue and
usually as you probably most of you all
know this is never without some hard and
soft constraints. So what you can see
here again we're following the the the
notion of demand and the action of
setting the price for specific products.
The objective is revenue. So demand
times price is usually revenue. So in
this case you can see how we try to
maximize the revenue by essentially
setting a specific counterfactual price
into the horizon. See what would be the
associated demand and this is uh omitted
for for simplicity but the entire
context alongside the price that we want
to kind of experiment with. We feed it
into the optimization and we let it kind
of go. The constraints that you can see
here on the side are just few examples
that are sometimes relevant when you try
to make a meaningful pricing policy
decision. For example, when I set a
specific price, I never want it to be um
exceeding specific bounds or I do not
want to introduce high high variance in
kind of consecutive pricing decisions or
that I want to have some ordering. For
example, I would never want an economy
ticket to be priced at a lower price
compared to um or for a higher price in
in compared to business, right? Uh
business class.
Okay. So, we we kind of defined the
fundamentals of how do we think uh one
could uh use quantitative capabilities
in order to answer um answer questions
that businesses sometimes have. And I
want to kind of connect it to why we
think agents work uh quite uh amazingly
here um when they are being uh provided
with those capabilities. And this is
mostly for for the reason that you know
the real question that a business might
ask is the questions are are open-ended.
Right? So this is um a quote but it it's
a general statement of a question that
might come up. uh in this quote it says,
"Well, we have an investigation where we
identify that prices of specific
products aren't really keeping up with
the demand that we're seeing in the
market and we want to see whether that
makes sense. We want to potentially
update our pricing policy. Right? So, so
we want to kind of have an agent to
understand what's going on in the
market, understand whether the current
uh policies that we have are are
sensible, and we're going to see um
we're going to let it kind of go.
Um and and what I want you guys to to
kind of grasp in in in your head before
we move on is that we have the many
reasons to believe that uh naive or
vanilla agents will actually fail in in
providing a reasonable answers that we
can we can really trust and they will
fail for pretty much the same reason
that have resulted from these tools that
I outlined to be even needed. Right? So
naive agents might not have a good
enough forecaster that is able to
generalize in out of distribution
scenarios or they don't might might not
even have a forecaster that could do any
meaningful forecast at all. I mean if I
were to give a cloud code um a query
predict how the price is going to look
like I would I would I would argue that
it's going to find it a bit difficult.
uh of course it doesn't have a uh an
optimization process that will allow us
to uh dynamically and and consistently
use constraints in order to maximize a
business objective and these are
examples that we believe that a naive
agent might might find it difficult to
to to come uh success. So this is kind
of the motivation I want you all to to
follow and in the following slides we're
d we're going to dive into the details
of what might be an opinionated way that
we think um an architecting quantitative
decision agent could be made possible
and we're going to see how um um we see
that um being rolled out. We're going to
dive into some code so um be prepared.
Um we're going to start with uh with the
market model, right? The market model is
Fetcher's model for predicting what's
going to happen with the market, right?
And there are many examples of what are
the relevant signals that the market
might have. We're going to dive into
those in a bit. But what you can see
here is a very simple, let's say almost
uh compiled Python code that kind of
goes through some of the configurations
that one might want to define before
running a pre-training multivariate time
time series forecasting module. So you
can see here um configurations for ray
hyperparameter tuning that represents
like information about input size some
of the hidden sizes of the internal uh
dynamics of neural network learning rate
and so on also we are defining here a
set of features those are the one that
I've kind of outlined at the beginning
information about the past that is known
information about the future that is
potentially uh also known and again I'm
following here an example from uh a
client that we have in the airline
industry. Most of the relevant features
here that in this example are outlined
as static features represents the cabin
um the direction of the flight and so on
and so forth. And we're going to uh
based on these configuration run a
simple training process. And again, I'm
I'm obviously being a bit um vague here
in the terminology, but one can think of
uh distribution-based loss that will be
used as criteria for the deep learning
uh architecture and some custom uh deep
neural network that is able to consume
information from a look back window and
predict that uh distribution into the
horizon. Yeah, go ahead.
Yeah,
>> it's it's a it's not a lag. It's a look
back window.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Um so yeah, so we're going to let it um
kind of go through. And by the way, for
those of you who are familiar with Andre
Karpathy's auto research, this is fully
compatible with that. So you can provide
us as context. You can kind of let it
learn loose. This is hyperparameter on
steroids, but we believe that we want
consistency for the pre-trained model.
We want some guarantees. So, we are not
yet comfortable kind of moving into
that. I'll be able to to kind of go into
that if you're interested if you'll jump
to our booth uh later on. And by the
way, if those who are interested, this
is following the terminology of the open
source time series framework uh from
Nyxla. Um if you're interested in kind
of learning more about time series, I
highly recommend. We're not working with
them. I I just feel that they're very uh
I I I feel comfortable kind of sharing
what they do because they really do best
practices. So if you're interested.
All right. So we talked about a
pre-training. Let's see exactly what are
the outputs of the time series uh
framework that we provide. Essentially
what is or what are the dynamics of the
market the way we see them. And this is
a simple understanding uh simple
representation. You know when we talked
about when we talk about demand usually
we are not talking about a demand value
but rather how demand differentiates or
what's the difference across different
price points. And if you've done
econometric 101, you know that demand is
usually portrayed by demand curves.
Right? So what you can see here is a
simple process where we load um some
pre-trained checkpoint of our model. We
load all of the uh information
containing um so know feature selection
encoding of the numerical and the
categorical features and so on and so
forth. Nothing uh pretty fancy going on
uh here. And we're going to run through
a specific um sample that we have been
provided with the pre-trained the
forward pass and we're going to provide
in this example we talked about general
distribution loss. Here we're talking
about a quantile forecast that predicts
how demand is going to look like not in
the sense of the demand value but rather
the demand quantiles. In this example
we're going through the 10th quantile,
the median quantile which is the 50th
and the 90th quantile. We provide some
data class that represents uh different
aggregation that we have on that
specific forecast. Uh looking through
the mean um kind of of the entire uh
horizon of the demand looking through
the specific revenue. So revenue is
price time demand. We kind of talked
about this uh explaining some measure of
uncertainty that we will will soon use
you know once we talked about um
quantile we can assess uncertainty but
not only that once we have an
information about the demand we can look
at its higher order derivatives to
understand elasticity to understand
where does the maximum of the revenue is
being obtained. These are very simple
but still non-trivial understanding of
market dynamics.
Okay, we talked about the math, we
talked about the code of the uh market
dynamic or the market uh model. Now
we're going to jump into the
optimization under constraints. So again
for for the sake of example, we're
running through a very simple data class
that go through price constraint
introducing lower upper demand
introducing some max steps. So you know
consecutive price policy values into the
horizon will not exceed a specific
threshold. And we have a very um trivial
but but but relevant uh private function
that we will then be using in order to
apply constraints during the
optimization process
in order to find again and I want to
remind you we're trying to come up with
an optimization that maximizes uh reward
which is revenue essentially invoking
the forward pass of the market model
understanding how demand is going to
look like distribution across the entire
horizon in this example we're just using
scypi minimize scaler
applying the constraints and providing a
helper function that will help us
simulate reward, simulate revenue into
the horizon. This is just kind of helper
function that will help us have a
guarantee of what optimization looks
like the way we envision it.
And this is an example I think shared
something quite similar uh previously.
What you can see here is that uh what
you see in here is the revenue landscape
as depicted by the market model at a
fixed time into into the horizon. And
the horizontal line that that protrudes
from from the uh um from the bottom here
represents some hard constraint that we
have for a specific product represented
by its price represented by y. In this
example, we're essentially saying um if
this is the revenue landscape, never
have the price policy recommend prices
below uh the point C. And if a global
maxima was attained at point A by
introducing the constraint, we are now
reluctant to find uh an optimum policy
that is only been obtained with the
constraints in a local maxima B. Of
course, the revenue landscape is rarely
this nice. It is rarely differentiable
but this is just to give you a bit of
intu intuition.
All right, we talked about the
capabilities. We talked about the
mathematical abstraction. We've talked
about how we can write them in a simple
terms in code. We want to plug it into a
harness. So what you can see here is how
we believe again a simple variant of of
how an agent could use those
capabilities. and we're going to go
through the process of injecting those
capabilities by multiple um um options
and we'll see how an agent could use
them. So one of the first thing that you
know comes to mind is that each one of
their capabilities we talked about the
market dynamics prediction we talked
about the optimization process. Let's
kind of wrap them in tools. This is just
one of the example and and again we're
not working um with cloud but what you
can see here is that we're using cloud
agent SDK which is pretty much cloud
code like in the sense of the
functionality that you might expect to
to be. Uh so if you're working with
cloud code, this should be pretty
straightforward for you to kind of
follow on. Um we're providing a pretty
simple wrapper to the prediction of the
market dynamics. So I hope you guys can
read but I'm going to be a bit verbal
going through that. Uh what you can see
here is that the predict market dynamics
tool is essentially a tool that is uh
provided with configuration in a pyantic
like structure. So the input would be
verified by the Asian P4 invoking the
actual uh prediction of the market
dynamics which is abstracted in a
capabilities py file. This is the
capabilities we talked about before and
we're returning a structured output with
the context exposing some of the market
dynamics output that we talked about the
quantiles themselves understanding of
elasticity and so on. and we kind of go
through the process of taking each and
every one of our capabilities and
wrapping them with a designated tool.
What you can see below and of course for
brevity I haven't included all of the
tools. What you can see below is is how
cloud SDK provides an abstraction to to
an MC MCP server. So there are the data
capabilities tools which are essentially
the these are the buckets in GCP. Please
go ahead and fetch the relevant data in
order to and again I want to remind you
we're going to provide an agent with a
question of are prices here sensible
right so we want to provide it with real
data we have an MCP tool to to help the
agent kind of fetch the relevant data we
also have uh what we call the fetcher
capabilities MCP that is essentially a
thin wrapper uh a server if you will of
all of the tools that we talked about
soon you're going to see how I'm using
specific clustering of the tools tools
at the bottom here. We have data tools
that kind of allows the the model allows
the agent to to to fetch real historical
information about the the market. We
have the large market model tools which
is essentially the prediction of the
market dynamics the optimization and
some tools concerning evaluation.
So okay, once we have the tools, we want
to define some structure that will allow
specific tools to be invoked by specific
sub aents. In this example, you can see
and again uh cloud SDK abstract those
pretty nicely. Uh if you're interested
in kind of diving into uh into that um
we have two functions that essentially
one of them is is an analyst factory and
one of them is an initial initializer of
an analyst. We're going through the
process of defining um three uh
designated sub aents and one um kind of
orchestrating agent. The orchestrator is
going to to be a revenue manager. It's
going to have a system prompt that is
relevant to what might uh you you think
would be relevant for a a revenue
manager that has under its disposal
three sub agents. Each one has the
designated capabilities. understanding
the dynamics of the market,
understanding how to provide pricing
policy and a QA analyst that will kind
of help making sure that the predictions
and the policies are sensible.
And this is how it's being defined.
Again, this is fully runnable uh code.
All right. Uh the final thing, this is
more kind of for meta analysis. Since
we're using uh specific capabilities, we
want to make sure that we uh hook them
and kind of log whatever information we
care for in a way that is customizable.
Um so usually when you kind of fire a
tool, there's a post tool use uh that is
being uh invoked and cloud SDK has a
specific hook matcher that kind of
allows you to grab specific um um
functionalities for in this example
after a tool has been uh called you want
to kind of catch that. You want to do
some custom behavior. In this custom
behavior, we want to define what we call
grounding. We want to see when the agent
was going through its reasoning whether
it were it was use utilizing uh the
specific tools that we have defined. So
this is just something that I wanted to
add uh for completeness.
At the end of the day uh claude agent
options consumes all of the things that
I outlined uh right now. So there's the
general revenue manager prompt which is
the prompt the system prompt that we
have for uh the agent uh that
orchestrates. We have all of the um
allow tools the MCP server the sub aents
and the hooks that I defined and we're
kind of going ahead and letting this
agent uh run. And this is a simple uh
query loop that we provide just for kind
of logging and printing the results as
they go. Uh but but this is pretty much
it.
All right. So, we talked about the
capabilities the the capabilities in in
terms of of real Python code. We talked
how you might um connect them to a
harness. And we want to run through an
experiment. And the following
experiments, two agents will be asked
the same question. One of them is a clot
agent. Essentially, cloud code harness.
It has reasoning. It has web access. It
could write and run its own code. It
could do whatever the hell it wants.
On the other hand, there's the fetcher
or the market model or the agent that
has the capabilities that allows it to
understand the market. But other than
that, it's going to be pretty much the
same.
We're going to ask them a simple
question. Is the price right? Now, what
you see here is real obviously
anonymized data from one of our clients.
You can see in a year-over-year analysis
how demand has been reduced for a
specific product at a specific market by
22% whereas prices for that specific
product have increased by more than 60%.
And we kind of want to kind of provide
this context uh to the agents and say
guys is this sensible? Uh the answer is
it's not trivial. One might say we one
might say it is because the price
increased that we are seeing uh demand
decreased but this might not be the
answer demand could be decreased because
something happened something else right
this is the data the outputs you know we
we we talked about the fact that we are
um uh hooking on whatever uh tools that
were called the output here that you can
see here at the top here is is kind of
the directory structure of the uh let's
say the vanilla agent and on the bottom
the agent that has the capabilities.
They both went ahead and provided um
some markdowns with some of the uh
thought process that they've done but
ultimately the two provided a
recommendation CSV increase the price
decrease the price by how much and we'll
see how they um differentiate.
Before I get into that um and maybe you
will start thinking about the intuition
if if you were to guess what were the
recommendations of those those two
agents would they even be the same um I
want to go through some of the kind of
meta analysis uh when it kind of seeing
seeing what the agents did so they were
bashing away right so cloud agent it
wrote some Python script it ran some
statistic it used pandas his favorite
tool and it kind of produced CSVs that
help him understand the historical data,
the patterns, the correlation for that
specific product in that specific market
and it kind of did quite quite a lot.
The market model agent on the other hand
well it has the capabilities. So he used
them he used them extensively and not
only that he aggregated the results of
utilizing the tools that hide behind the
scene the capabilities um parsing them
building product list on top of them
aggregating optimization results and and
take it at face value was using much
more tools.
Now if you cluster the tool call per
analyst. So we talked about the fact
that we have four agents right four
three of them are analysts and the one
that orchestrate the three is a revenue
manager tool. One thing that we found
quite quite interesting is that um the
the fetcher the the tool that the agent
that has the capabilities was going
through the process of invoking um
predicting how demand is going to look
like but for one of the product it has
identified that there is some
uncertainty in the prediction. It could
be due to the fact that historical data
was not substantial enough. But
regardless and this was the work of the
QA analyst, he flagged using the
evaluate forecast tool that that there
is high certainty high uncertainty in
the predictions of one of the in in one
of the products in one of the market. He
kind of raised it to his boss the
revenue manager who is turn redispatched
the price analyst on the subset of the
market and therefore you can see kind of
the spike. So they were kind of playing
between one another, flagging some
concerns, going back to to the
capabilities and going through the
process. At the end in a market where
there are six uh specific products, the
fetcher analysts have recommended to uh
to ship five prices. So five price
recommendations and one of the markets
where he identified uncertainty, he'd
have flagged it for the revenue manager.
And this was part of the rationale mark
markdown and part of the
recommendations. The unaded agent of
course shipped everything. It had no
mechanism to evaluate uncertainty in the
market.
All right. So kind of zooming into one
of the product at the at the top you can
see just catting the recommendation CSV
in a product uh and again the top is is
the unaded agent and at the bottom the
the fetcher agent with the capabilities
for a specific product that at that
specific point in time was priced at
$1,100.
The vanilla agent was recommending a
price increase by $200 and the fetcher
agent was actually recommending a price
decrease by about $250. [snorts]
So they were essentially um having the
same data, different reasoning and
absolutely different uh conclusion both
in magnitude and in direction.
Let's see some of the thought process.
Um what you can see here is uh an
estimation of revenue and demand and at
the kind of white uh white dot uh the
current $1,100
uh of the specific product of interest,
right? Um let's see what the fetcher
agent understood. So the fetcher agent
kind of went ahead and invoked the
market model and understood that due to
the fact that at this spec specific
price um there is a elasticity that an
absolute value is greater than one he
recommends to decrease the price and he
found that in an unconstrained setup the
decrease should fall to the 828
part where elasticity gets his maximum.
Elasticity by the way is how much in
percentage uh does price change cause to
demand change. And kind of quoting from
the rationale at the at the right here,
this is just a quote from from one of
the output assets of the agent. Demand
on the route
is elastic every 1% price reduction
yields about 1.4% more bookings more
than offsetting the fair reduction in
revenue terms. Right? So it has did its
analysis based on grounded tools that
provided it understanding of how the
market is going to evolve and therefore
how to recommend an updated price.
Ultimately the revenue manager agent has
used this and kind of invoked the price
optimization tool. It has found that
because it is constrained and by looking
through the entire set of departure
dates it could not meet uh the price
where maximum is really obtained but
essentially decided to sit uh not far
away from there at $863
in the process and in the rationale it
has identified that there's a holiday
happening at that departure and and kind
of use that in order to kind of showcase
that averaging demand across price in
this market at specific dates where In
some cases, demand might be even higher
due to holiday. Um could result in kind
of pricing uh much higher and ultimately
it had fixated and similarly um to to
the to the market model at $800 again
and 30 and $63.
The revenue manager quite satisfied took
those recommendations rounded up for
simplicity sake and shipped the fair the
price 850
and this is what it done right in
estimation in estimation of the revenue
this has caused more than 6% uh uplift
in that specific product.
Now the um the unaded agent it was
trying its best. It really did. Uh but
in the process it has confused
correlation for causation. It had ran
analysis on correlation in specific
markets that do not necessarily
correlate with one another. And I'm
going to [snorts] quote you once again.
Uh demand elasticity is negligible in a
specific bucket of of dates that he was
investigating. correlation of nearly
zero. So raising the floor carries near
zero demand destruction risk.
Essentially [snorts] it has has wrongly
identified that there is no correlation.
What it had done by mistake is
correlating products that shouldn't be
correlating with one another. It was it
was never fixating a specific product
and varying the price in a
counterfactual manner and therefore have
decided that it could increase the
prices without the demand to fall. But
ultimately and unfortunately for him
elasticity
um is a real thing and in the process in
a kind of unbiased revenue estimation it
has resulted in almost 8% um uh revenue
um uplift or a negative revenue uplift.
All right. So what we have seen here
let's talk about this whole pipeline end
to end and kind of call it a day. Um we
talked about a general harness. We
defined one manager that runs a loop,
reviews it and kind of aggregates um
whatever it had found. We talked about
uh sub agents that has specialties. They
split the work. Each get its own tools.
They don't share contexts. They don't
confuse with tools that might be
similar. They have a QA mechanism that
is um unbiased and is able to check the
assets of its counterpart sub aents. And
crucially they all use quantitative
capabilities. This is where the
mathematic is at. This is where the
formulas are being implemented. This is
where the revenue manager agent knows
that is not expert in and he is
delegating in order to make a meaningful
and reliable answer. And of course by
grounding and seeing what what's
happened in the process he's able to
come up with recommendations that
compared to a unaded agent are
substantially different. So if there's
one thing I want you guys to take from
here is that we feel that there is great
power by joining um large language model
capabilities of orchestration and
agentic harness development but knowing
when and how to delegate the capabil to
capabilities that will tell you that you
can trust and rely uh the outcomes. So
while the large language model
orchestrate the capabilities like the
one that cover all of the intelligence
that we develop in fetcher those are the
one that carries the guarantees. So
thank you so much.
[applause]
>> Thank you so much.
All righty. Now please help me welcome
our next speaker Krishnaram Kintapati.
Krishna Ram is the chief science
scientist at Oracle Health. Krishna Ram
if you could make your way to the stage.
There we go. Please put your hands
together for Krishna.
[applause]
Take a few couple minutes for the
slides.
>> Sure.
>> This is a good time to practice.
>> Yeah. Uh hi everyone. Uh while we're
waiting for the slides to load up, uh
just a raise of hands. How many of you
are from academia?
Okay. Uh and how many from industry?
Anybody from government or NOS's?
All right. So I see uh at least I could
kind of see maybe a a larger proportion
from industry and a sizable number of
folks from academia. Um so while while
we're waiting uh for these slides to
load uh let let me just um give some
feel for what we are doing. Um as uh I
was introduced I'm the chief scientist
for the healthcare AI efforts at Oracle.
So we have been looking at some of the
uh challenges in healthcare the
challenges that clinicians face every
day on a day-to-day basis. So these um
uh these range from spending a lot of
time on say the electronic health record
systems or spending a lot of time going
through the patient records and so forth
and not being able to spend as much time
facetoface interacting with the
patients. Uh so that's a that's a kind
of broad problem we are we're kind of
looking at solving. Um so while we we we
are still waiting on the slides um so
let me just give give some context on
where I'm coming from. So I I have been
at Oracle for almost two years uh
helping grow these efforts and launch uh
our flagship product clinical agent and
uh its varants. So before this I I have
been over the last two decades or so
working on uh problems related to
trustworthiness
starting with data privacy, bias
fairness, explanability uh a
observability and so forth. All right.
So here we we have um
okay so let me start with some of the
where the state of healthcare today. Uh
today we have a number of different
challenges. So we have the challenge of
shortage of physicians or more broadly
clinicians.
We have the problem of
burnout and administrative overhead
experienced by clinicians. There are
surveys showing even before COVID
pandemic that about 80%age of clinicians
were experiencing burnout
causing them to quit the profession or
planning to cut uh the healthcare
industry as as a whole. Then we also
have on the other other hand uh the
amount of time that a patient gets to
spend with the physician is reducing
because the physicians are asked to see
more and more patients and even in this
small amount of say 15 minutes typically
the the provider or the physician will
be spending a good chunk of time looking
at the computer and maybe not as much
looking at the patient. And all of these
factors along with maybe several other
systemic factors result in a number of
errors in uh health care for example
resulting in as much as 400,000
preventable deaths in the US alone. And
of course these are not limited to us.
These are problems in many countries
across the world. At the same time we
are seeing that the health care costs
have been going up. For example, in the
US, it is estimated that around $1
trillion
is is uh associated with the
administrative overhead or
administrative burden in healthcare. So
the natural question is this is not
sustainable. What can we do about this?
How can we bring down the cost and also
improve the quality of uh the the the
care that the patients receive today? uh
this is where
I think that AI has a huge role and in
fact this is not just thinking it's AI
is already being used across healthcare
and being adopted rapidly the challenge
that we are looking at is how can AI
help reduce ad administrative overhead
clinician burnout and so forth so that
hopefully it results in better patient
outcomes and and since this is the
domain of healthcare. How do we do this
in a trustworthy manner? How do we
ensure patient safety? How do we ensure
that all the regulations are followed
and so forth? So, with this context, um
let me
let me kind of go into more into what we
are doing. As I mentioned earlier, our
goal is to reduce the time doctors spend
entering data or searching patient
records or typing notes and so on and
instead spend more time interacting with
the patient which is the thing that they
or they the reason they came to the
profession in the first place. Um
towards this we have built and uh
deployed uh a product called clinical AI
agent where we first focused on the task
of automatically capturing the medical
nodes by listening to the doctor patient
conversation of course with the consent
of the patient and the doctor and then
building on top of this automatically
capturing uh various orders placed by
the doctor like X-rays, labs,
medications and so forth and going
beyond that helping the doctor when
before they go and see a patient in
terms of
what what is the summary or what is the
gist of why the patient is there and
what what are the relevant parts from
the patient record for that u to to go
into more uh specifics like we have been
building this to be voice first and
multimodel
um something that works across devices
ranging from mobile or web interface,
desktop and so forth and also in a way
where it takes the provider context into
account. It knows the preferences of the
physicians as well as the patient
context the re the reason the patient is
here the history of the patient and so
on and do this in a way which is as
proactive as possible. uh for example if
a new lab report has arrived we want to
suggest what might be the next best
course of action in terms of the care
pathway for the patient for example
uh there are a number of uh technical
nuances behind this today let me just
give a uh one example of this just as a
flavor of this so by the way uh here is
a a link to a live demo of the system.
Uh so one of the key components of our
system is what we called the multi- aent
orchestrator.
Suppose that the doctor is looking at uh
Samantha's uh record and wants to know
how how her her vitals trending. The
doctor might ask show me the recent
labs.
So given this query we need to figure
out whether we need to uh search in
structured records containing the labs.
Do we need to search over unstructured
data like the medical nodes? We need to
take into account the UI context uh the
context of the the patient and so forth
and do the do this in a way which
supports multi-turn conversations.
And to do this um even though this query
might be simple you can imagine a number
of other uh settings like are there side
effects of the medications that Samantha
is taking now or
what might be the best course of action
for Samantha given her past records and
the new uh lab lab results that have
arrived. Um to do this the orchestrator
has a library of tools and skills. It
needs to decide which is the right one
to invoke. Um then it it invokes those
tools and it also has uh different types
of guardrails. guardrails on at the
input side especially if this is not
doctor phasing but say patient phasing
making sure that uh any queries which
are sensitive or which require
appropriate uh escalation due to medical
emergencies are handled appropriately.
Likewise god rails once we get the
response from the agent on the output
side then of course we also want the
latency and costs to be contained. So we
do a number of optimizations such as uh
caching or parallel computations or
deciding when the query needs to be
routed to a reasoning model a complex
reasoning model and when it simpler uh
language model or even a deterministic
Python code would suffice to get the
response. So making those decisions at
runtime so that we save both the latency
and the cost. Uh, of course there are a
number of other optimizations that I
won't be going into today. Um as we move
towards not just a multi-agent
architecture for a specific application
but a multi- aent health care system as
a whole uh there are of course a number
of different stakeholders involved
ranging from patients, doctors on the
administrative side, the folks involved
on the payer side and so on. And of
course a number of systems including the
electronic health records and different
tasks ranging from search
uh document document summarization or uh
understanding the u medical coding and
so forth. How do we do this in a manner
which is which where all these agents
interact with each other. Um at the same
time there are aspects like a number of
things that can go wrong. uh if you're
interested please take a look at uh the
tutorial that we presented at the ACM
conference on agentic systems and AI
recently um just to give an example
there are challenges around evaluation
the evaluation that works offline may
not translate to online either because
the assumptions are no longer true or
the distribution of the patients may
have changed.
We also need to make sure that we take
the business metrics and map them to
appropriate applied science metrics
which we can measure and iterate on.
Then there are problems like omissions.
Uh if you are presenting a summary of
the patient to the doctor unlike say web
search or other systems here recall is
extremely important. If you miss
something which is medically uh
pertinent in the summary that can lead
to patient safety.
So, so to while we are doing this, let
me just illustrate this with
another setting in the medical imaging
scenario.
So, here the task is how do we encode
clinical workflows uh when it comes to
something like chest X-ray
interpretation? How do we leverage tools
that clinicians use today uh and so
forth? Um and again like even in this
work we have an orchestrated agent. Then
we have a number of sub agents inspired
by clinical workflows. There is
something called ABCDE system in um
medical imaging stands for airway
breathing and so on. And we have the sub
aents which are invoked um in parallel
and then there is a synthesizer which
combines potentially conflicting uh
results from uh these sub agents and
then decides what's the best course of
action. Um again like as you all know
healthcare is heavily regulated. Uh so
this motivates
uh some of the other work we do whether
it is in the data privacy space or uh
bias and fairness space. uh in the
interest of time let me skip this and
let me conclude with the following uh
takeaway uh in a setting like healthcare
it's very important to understand the
domain uh not just focus on model
development but also on the data
validation on the evaluation methodology
and so forth and it's important to
iterate with the clinicians uh
understanding their needs having some
early version out and iterating based on
that and of course we we use frontier
models But those may not have all the
healthcare specific nuances. So building
domain and task specific knowledge and
encoding these in uh in the form of a
semantic knowledge graph and uh semantic
data layer is very important. And as I
alluded to uh trust safety are extremely
important and here is just an an example
of a process we follow uh in the form of
AI review for health. Uh and let me
conclude with this and uh happy to talk
to you offline if there are questions.
Thank you.
>> Thank you so much.
All right. I know you just clapped, but
you're going to have to clap again very
soon. So, please help me welcome Vin
Katpot, who is the director of AI for
mental health program at the University
of Toronto.
Okay. All right. So, while the slides
are loading, um, so I'm based at the
University of Toronto. I lead the AI for
mental health program there. I'm also
the u national mental health community
of practice lead within the temporary
center for AI in medicine which is based
at the University of Toronto. It brings
together all the universities across the
country. My focus within that is mental
health. Um so I've been interested in
this domain for many years. Um I'm a
psychiatrist, a clinician scientist and
my interest has been principally because
a lot of the developments uh in AI have
been based upon how the human brain
works. Um deep learning is cortical
representation to start off. um
reinforcement learning is subcortical
and um
one-third of my program is around
reverse engineering these systems. I
won't be going into that today. Most of
my program, twothirds of my program is
around um um automating workflows in the
clinical context in mental health. So
that's what I'll be speaking about
today. Um you'll you'll see as I present
that um our usual paradigm is we
identify a workflow that we're
interested in where it may be possible
to automate. We develop the automations
uh either a single agent or a multi-
aent system and with um a bot playing
the role of the end user we essentially
show with a sandbox environment and
simulations that it actually works well.
Um and then what may be different from
some of the talks and presentations
you've seen today. I'm a clinician. I'm
a clinical trialist. I run a lot of
clinical trials. Um I want to see if
these things which in the virtual
environments or simulation setup tends
seems to work. Does it really work in
actual clinical care? Um so that's what
I do quite a bit. I run clinical trials
across disciplines.
um depression, PTSD,
um anxiety
on the prevention side as well um and
more recently in uh mental health and
Alzheimer's as well. Um I did check all
the slides working so
I can keep on going but
yeah there you go. So um
so I' I've already introduced myself. Um
so those are my disclosure slides. So
everything I present today I'll be
giving a big picture view. I won't be
getting into the details. It's all
published or it's in the public domain
or it's actually coming out in the next
two or three weeks. This is my
disclosure slide. Um so I'll give one or
two examples. I've already given the
brieface as to what we do. we show that
these single or multi-agent systems work
uh in a simulation environment and then
we do clinical trials two to three year
clinical trials. Um so I'll give
examples in each of these contexts. I've
already mentioned this as my real
interest in the domain. Onethird of my
program is around the interpretability
side. I won't be getting into any of
those details today. This has been my
inspiration to be in this domain for
many years now. All my my uh you know
presentation today will be one or two
examples along where we have automated
workflows.
Um so I don't need to go through this
for this crowd but I'm just presenting
this that about three or four years ago
as we started realizing that we're
moving into an autonomy range uh going
from various levels of autonomy we
started to think what would this mean in
clinical care in mental health. So if
there's one um slide to take home from
the presentation today and this will be
my corner stone and I'll keep bringing
this up a couple of times. So so this
was three four years ago us trying to
conceptualize what could be the role of
these agents in a human in the loop
model in mental health. So we came up
with this idea of collaborative
assistive semi-autonomous agents um and
then trying to see what the role of the
human in that loop would be. This is
another way to look at it. What could be
some assistive a u capabilities, some
collaborative ones and then some
semi-autonomous ones. Um I think the one
example of generative AI which most
clinicians identify with and is in use
is the AI scribe. The previous speaker
was also mentioning this. Um a lot of
the others actually require quite a bit
of evidence. So I'm not going to go into
the examples um to with each of them but
I'll give you one or two to give you a
flavor in all of these four domains. So
clinical care. So this is um us
automating my day-to-day clinic uh with
different intake agents um with either a
single agent or a multiple agent right
through the clinical workflow from when
we start seeing the patient to when we
discharge them. We have published on
each of them and we are now actually
working towards clinical trials. This is
the oops just want to go back. So this
is the front end and the back end of the
clinic. Um we run clinical trials
because it's not important. Uh it's not
enough if at that particular workflow
the agent is non-inferior to the human
doing the task. There are a lot of other
ecosystem changes. There's change
management, there's service redesign, a
number of other things need to happen.
So that's where we do mixed methods to
see what what does it take even if it's
efficacious for this tool to actually be
adopted. We also include cost benefit
because that's also a critical factor.
So I'll give you two examples here. This
is on the clinical side. So we know in
mental health that measurement based
care makes a difference. So this is the
equivalent of blood sugar for diabetes
um or your blood pressure for
hypertension. um clinicians do scales or
patients do scales um like the PHQ or
the GAD 7 for over two decades it's been
really difficult to get these things
done so we essentially automated um
taking unstructured data so think of
your ambient scribe in some sense and
the next step to that to to actually
generate the scales and also prompting
clinicians if they have not collected
this information this is moving into
trials through epic at our hospital
sites u this is multi-agent system to do
diagnostic interviewing. So essentially
we took the DSM the operationalized DSM
which is this kit and you see a multi-
aent system there um um one which is
asking the questions the another which
is overseeing it does not allow you to
move on to the next module and then
which follows the skip logic within the
skid uh and then you have an
orchestrator/diagnoser
and we have shown that with a bot
playing the role of the um patient with
all kinds of DSM complicated diagnosis.
This actually does quite well and it's
now in clinical trials where we're
showing uh where we would like to see if
this is useful or not. In the clinical
trials, we are purposefully positioning
this from mild to moderate symptoms. We
know that the person with severe
psychosis or depression or Alzheimer's
is not going to be able to use this. So,
I'll move on to education. Um I think
everyone is worried about deskkilling
that people are going to use GPT and not
learn what they need to know. Um that's
a legitimate concern and needs to be
addressed in different ways. Um what we
have tried to do is it takes 10 years to
train a clinician, four years of medical
school, four to six years of residency
training. Can we accelerate people
gaining competencies through use of
agentic AI? So essentially we broke down
the competencies that people are
supposed to attain by the time they
finish their training and we looked at
each competency both in Canada and in
the US the respective boards. Um and we
came up with a multi- aent [snorts]
system here. So we have a bot playing
the role of a patient. We have a bot
playing the role of the clinician. And
with the bot playing the role of the
resident
um who would want to learn skills of
interviewing. How does a resident or a
medical student for that matter learn
how to do clinical interviewing which is
the core skill of a clinician by doing
this repeatedly and presenting to the
clinician and getting feedback. So
essentially we simulated the whole thing
with a multi- aent system and we're
working to have seven of the largest
clinical training programs um deploy
this. One arm will do the training as
they're doing now and the other arm will
see if this augmented by what they're
doing now would lead to people gaining
their competencies sooner. I.e. rather
than taking five years to finish your
training, could you gain competencies in
three or four? In theory this this
sounds at least if you look at the
system we have built it um it sounds to
work well but I come as a clinical
trialist from a skeptical perspective on
these things that most of these things
are not going to work at least in the
way we think it would work but the few
things which would work will have a
transformative effect. So this is
another variant of that a multi-agent
system to help residents learn basic
principles of psychotherapy. So,
cognitive behavioral therapy,
motivational interviewing, and you have
the system. It is like you're
interviewing a patient within that
framework. So, I'll move on. I'm not
going to dwell on this, but um um I've
been over the last 5 10 years doing a
lot of systematic reviews and meta
analysis. Um I think I won't be doing it
in a couple of years. We will have
living systematic reviews and meta
analysis. With the way things are
progressing, what we've been trying to
do is not end toend automation, but look
at specific points within the systematic
review and meta analysis pipeline and
what its role is. Um, it takes hours um
and often weeks for my research
assistants to just go through and
compare um where the errors are as they
pull through um publication. So this is
one paper on the quantitative side. We
did the same on the qualitative side
where we do thematic analysis and we
compared the themes which would come
through qualitative analysis along with
um um you know as compared to the one
with u generative AI and we're building
in some automations into this but the
bottom line is not end to end still
human in the loop and this was with the
previous versions of uh GPT but I don't
think it's more different with the
current versions either but basically
what we're showing is that up a certain
level of complexity and within
particular points within the workflow
you are able to automate them. This is
the same with um um another domain which
is uh in terms of data processing um for
EEG analysis. So um quality improvement
this is my last example within this
realm um where um so this was during the
pandemic clinicians started doing um
assessments um virtually and we wanted
to know what's the nature of the
relationship between the patient and the
physician in the virtual settings. Um
we've gone from seeing people in person
to virtually. So essentially this was
multimodal. We used different data
streams um using unstructured data to
produce the working alliance inventory.
The working alliance inventory is the
proxy for the nature of the relationship
between the patient and the physician.
So this is gradually being moved into
clinical trials. So um I'll I'll go back
to this um you know situating this in my
uh presentation again. I've given a few
examples along this um agentic AI road
map where we're actually developing
assistive agents, collaborative agents
and semi-autonomous agents. I have two
more slides and then I'll end. We we've
been also looking at various different
components of these uh agents being able
to deliver therapy. Um so these papers
are published. Um and what we see is
that as the level of complexity
increases so we essentially forced uh
the agent to be able to do motivational
interviewing and after a certain level
of complexity um it is not able to
perform it loses its guardrails.
This will be my penultimate slide. So
here um we've been looking at if these
systems are to independently deliver
therapy, what is the nature of the
interaction and what's the what is the
importance of the value system within
it. So here we looked at low safety
guardrails versus high safety guardrails
and we were able to show that the safety
guardrails has a significant impact in
terms of how the agent is actually
perceived. So this is my last slide. So
we looked at what the world is doing in
this domain. Um um and it's quite
important that to note that in spite of
all the the the um um possibilities for
what these agents could do, there's only
one randomized control trial now coming
to two with the the bot last year with
Genai based tools. there's a real
critical need to have clinical trials
and that's what my team is uh
significantly involved in doing. Thank
you.
That was wonderful. All righty. So, uh a
really quick announcement or service
announcement. Uh I know there's a couple
of really exciting speakers coming up.
Um there we are getting some crowding on
the end and I know there's a lot of
space right here in the middle. So, if
the participants on the periphery, you
can squeeze into the middle seats up
there and um help your fellow attendees
find seats. That would be really lovely.
I would also like to point out there are
some seats up there in the second floor
and also to the right here.
Thank you. Lovely.
And and for anyone who's sitting on the
stairs, can you please find a seat? We
can't allow that because of uh fire
risks. So, if you can move to a seat. I
know. Apologies.
We expect more people to come in in a
few minutes. So, the better we do now,
the better we'll be in a few minutes.
Fantastic. All righty. Help me welcome
our next presenter.
Shia
Gagabi. Uh, sorry, Gaggabi is from
Nvidia. She is a deep learning scientist
from Nvidia. Please help me welcome
Shia.
Yeah. Hi everyone. I'm Shia from Nvidia.
So I'm working as a deep learning
scientist and our team is mostly working
on post training reasoning model uh for
finance uh using neotron model LLM model
for Nvidia. Today I'm going to talk
about uh general goal of our team and uh
what's the challenges we are facing uh
going through an examples to show the
challenges specifically and finally
showing our result and impact on
industry.
about the goal. So our goal is basically
sharing a open-source model that is
doing the finance reasoning so everyone
can use it. But it's not just sharing a
checkpoint so everyone can load it and
run the model but we want to share the
whole pipeline. We want to share our
data open so everyone can use our data.
Not only that they can generate the data
using our pipeline using our recipe, our
model and using our environment and
pipeline. So basically we want to share
all orchest orchestra that how we are
going through this process
but before that let's go through an
example and show why this is challenging
why the finance is the issue and we are
focusing on that. So just the big
picture that if for the finance model to
answer a finance question it should go
through multi-term reasoning uh so it
should go just basically calling
multiple tools doing the web search um
retrieving the different filing sec
filing and not only retrieving them it's
the long document it's the complex
document different structure
unstructured data structured data model
should understand all these document and
not only understand that it should do
the financial math on those document and
at the end site what part of this
document was helpful to answer the
question so to clarify it let's go
through an example so let's say
calculate the inventory turnover for US
steel in 2024 before so model to answer
this question should know that uh what's
the turnover formula and how to
calculate that not only that what kind
of the filing what kind of the form is
needs to be called from which tool from
web uh from SEC and when is calling do
the know extraction understanding all of
those document and calculate the formula
as you are seeing at the bottom of the
slide and the this I guess the last step
is site uh which part of this document
was helpful for the model. So we can say
these are the answer is based on
evidence and we can confirm this is the
correct one or not.
Uh but let's see how the models
currently are doing on this benchmark.
So we look at one of the famous
benchmark that has been recently
released on finance and this is the
result. The best closed model is
approximately 64%.
And open source model performance is
only 60%. They recently actually
released a little more complicated
finance benchmark and the best
performance currently is only 58%. So
you can see how much gap we we you know
we have to fill in.
Uh to show our contribution to summarize
I summarize it in four different
pillars. Uh we have done four main
contribution. First is sharing two SG
pipeline document based SG template
based SG. We shared our data publicly.
We have more than one million data that
you can access it right now. We trained
some models using our own data based on
our pipeline using SFD recipe, RL recipe
and we we saw a great improvement on
those model performance. Our pipeline
also supporting RL fine-tuning using
tool call and all in all in one
pipeline. Not only that we already have
two customers finance institute that of
course the security is important for
them because they are using finance data
uh but they can use our pipeline without
accessing to the internet so they don't
need to be about need to don't need to
be worry about the uh security
and it's already enterprise ready so you
can use our pipeline
uh so to show that how improvement we
made through this pipeline and based on
the data we generate you can After
fine-tuning coin models or neos model,
we have seen at about 11% uh on on coin
model and 7% on neos model performance.
Not only that without losing any um any
uh any um any accuracy uh we reach 25%
less token usage. Uh which you know less
token less cost better life.
So how we have done that? We have done
we have done all of this through one
pipeline orchestrated under NV flow. You
can do all the synthetic data generation
model fine-tuning evaluation and oral
training only on one pipeline. And not
only that we made a big important
decision in our pipeline having the
shared single environment and what does
that mean? It means all the synthetic
data generation SF tuning or tuning all
of them is just using the same tools
same format. So no need to no need for
the being worry about being consistent.
All in all we invite you to collaborate
with us. Our call is code data all of
them is shared publicly. So you can use
it and feel free to reach out to us for
more collaboration. Yeah. Thank you for
your time.
That was awesome. All righty. Uh,
another public service announcement. Uh,
we are reaching capacity and so if we
don't kind of like squeeze in every seat
we have in the middle, we are going to
have to close the doors for other
attendees. So, if you could kind of
concentrate in the middle, especially
that row over there, um, that would
really help all the attendees find
seating. And a reminder, no no one no
seating on the stairs. Um, again, there
are seats up here on the right and up
there on the left that are available and
look fancy. They're like balcony seats.
So,
thank you. Really appreciate it.
I love it. Humanity coming together.
You don't see it often nowadays.
All righty. I can now announce our next
presenter. Please help help me welcome
John Rav Shendi. He is the CTO of the
Thalis Group.
John Rav.
Thank you. Hello everyone.
And I guess big applause for you guys
for staying so late. We are running a
little bit late as everyone probably
realize.
I am going to run through my slides
pretty quickly. Uh probably skip some.
So if you want to chat please reach out.
So
when
basically what we're doing is we're
building security architects, frameworks
as well as looking at multiple things
within our operating environment. Uh be
it using our own internal systems as
well as systems that other end users
will be leveraging. um hopefully very
near. One of the things that bothered me
as I started looking at this was and we
all know what happened last week or a
week before where an agent decided to
do its own thing, right? Um so for me
what we're looking at is what are our
agents doing? How are we governing our
agents? What sort of challenges should
we be concerned about with our agents in
an operating environment? You heard some
really wonderful presentations today. Um
there was one super technical one with a
lot of code up there and essentially we
are doing a little bit of the same when
you think about orchestration, when you
think about runtime, when you think
about prompt, when you think about
prompt engineering and so on. So for us
when we thought about this situation,
not the one last week, but it occurred,
but we were thinking hypothetically what
happens if an agent decides to do what
it wants to do outside the limits and
bounds of what its intent is supposed to
be. I think I'm blocking you. Sorry.
Good. Yeah. So for us what we wanted to
look at was really look beyond the model
and look at the control boundary itself.
So this is standard you know Gartner's
projections. Um I'm sure a lot of you
here there's a lot of folks from
industry you know Gartner provides a lot
of metrics. Um these are forecast
metrics where enterprise are
vehemently or rigorously deploying or
analyzing agents or machine learning
plus LLMs
uh to execute on certain functions as
you saw in some of the presentations
before
um they say over 40% of that will fail
by 2027. That's a projection, right? Um,
when it comes to securing our
environments,
this is not an industrial benchmark.
It's a survey, but 14.4%
of organizations
are really looking at it from that
security perspective. 14.4%.
What do you guys think about that?
As engineers,
how many engineers are in the room?
Oh lord, almost the entire room. So as
engineers, we are told I feel more
relaxed now. I feel more comfortable. As
engineers, we are told, hey, we got to
build this. We got to ship it, you know,
and get it out the door, right? Ship it,
get it out the door, test it, so on.
Then audit comes in. And when audit
comes in, they put the brakes on it. And
I'll give you guys a quick story. Um
I was working on a system and we were
building we're doing fine and audit came
to me and said hey
we just checked the agents privileges
and entitlements
and it seems as though they could just
do anything they want.
Yeah. Right. They could have. Um so
basically audit came in and put brakes
on what we were supposed to do. We had
to stop. We had to re-engineer. We had
to work with the identity team. We had
to build identities and we had to ensure
with those identities we had a signed
intent. And that signed intent as
everyone knows is sort of a contract
that defines what the agent should be
doing based on the outcomes it should be
delivering
in theory. Right?
So
this basically
is our environment before AI, right?
Forget the downstream agents on the
right. The user SAS business systems.
This is typically how an environment
ran. It was linear. We know what we were
asking systems to do. We know what users
were doing and we were able to put
governance controls security metrics
around those things.
Today what do we have [snorts]
when a user or an agent or a user and an
agent is working everything comes
together. So a user executes a request
that user can call a an agent models.
You heard about orchestration. I'm not
going to get into that for the sake of
time. And basically what we have here is
an entire ecosystem that's taken a life
of its own in real time simultaneously.
So what do we have to do? what we are
doing uh at at thalis we are looking at
multiple things from the execution the
runtime governance as well as evidence
layer because simply saying hey we're
going to follow linear processes we're
going to follow a linear governance
model we're going to follow basic
testing that we do for software uh we're
going to embed QA and so on is not
enough today right simply because we're
looking at workflows that are occurring
in tandem. We are looking at functions
that are tied to those workflows. At
sometimes we're not sure who is
responsible, who's accountable for those
functions within those workflows. So now
we have to build a database or a
collection of transactions that has
records and what those transactions when
they are executing what is the impact
how can we build risk metrics based on
those impact and then create that
evidence layer. So basically at the
bottom we're subdividing everything
based on a human request
delegated authority and delegated
authority you you you guys have heard uh
sub agents and so on and basically the
challenge and the concern for me and my
team is when we assign um privileges
entitlements to a sub agent is that sub
agent acting as it should. If it's
acting on behalf of another agent and it
inherits the privileges and the
entitlements
um the authority authorizations
of the primary agent
should that be happening, right? And
most of us already know it should not be
happening, right? Um and most of us in
this room are working on making sure
that should not be happening. But we are
a finite group over in larger in
industry. The challenge I'm seeing is
people are skipping steps because we
need to build and ship. And if we build
and ship, we open ourselves up to risk.
So for us with that evaluance layer,
what we want to do, we're not looking so
much as at the agent as much as we're
looking at the control path. So the
control path is dynamic. So we have to
have hooks into that control part to
basically assess in real time where
something could go wrong to predict what
could go wrong and to define an outcome
when something goes wrong and then build
risk controls against that
right and you know
quite a few times I've given several
talks and everybody talks talks about
observability and governance and we see
observability and governance
interchanged a lot. Have you guys seen
that?
Yeah. Isn't it frustrating?
So for us observability is good. We can
see what's happening right? But can we
do something about it? That's the
question. And then when we think about
governance, we know that
we're seeing something occurring because
the model is executing. But we need to
be able to assess that control path and
then apply governance on that control
path based on an outcome. And that
outcome basically
exists to enforce decisions and those
decisions are basically bound to
identity, policy and authorization.
So with that then we can build decision
matrix. Once we have that data and we
build decision ma matrix then on the
control path itself we can then enforce
controls within that execution path
based on risk to the control path as we
see it. So they're observability plus
governance. They're not replaceable.
They don't substitute each other but
they work in tandem and in hand in hand.
Somebody told me once that
AI is all about software. What do you
guys think? Yes or no? Yes. Hands up.
No.
Yeah. Sorry. Yes. Um, for me, sorry
guys, I think I messed up this slide.
But, um,
let's just jump into it, right?
So as we are running systems and as
we're testing our systems, we built um
an entire I would say for one of a
better word, we built a contract and we
built a database that with all the
agents within our environment. We we
basically defined what those agents were
doing, what they were interacting with,
what tools they were calling and what
systems and so on were being engaged and
basically that's our declared authority.
Now when everything was running,
guess what happened?
We saw variances, right? We saw
variances that was not what we told the
things to do in the declared state, the
declared authority. So basically
what we started to do was analysis
around that variance.
So with that variance, we basically
built that across our runtime trust
plane and we were comparing
delegate uh sorry declared versus
observed and the metrics from identity
delegation policy risk and the evidence
lay I showed you guys earlier. Now all
of that is good.
Some people say drift is bad. What do
you guys think?
Yes,
probably. No. Yeah, not necessarily.
Drift is not necessarily bad, right? We
need to know the delta.
So, basically when we looked at our
environments,
what we did was we built explained
variants that and we categorized those
as shown allowed, approved, drift, and
control failure. What do you think was
the most important metric we looked at
there?
Two minutes. Control failure. That was
the most important metrics we look at.
Thank you. You got it. So
I have two minutes
with this. When we were building our
engineering environment, we basically
constrained it on four
constraints here. And we were looking at
you know I spoke about effiral agents.
We looked at the drift from what we were
seeing. And then as someone mentioned
earlier when we the healthcare gentleman
from Oracle mentioned when we build
systems we look at latency right and
that affects our costs and so on. So
that was another metric we looked at and
we took those three, we took the data
from that and we built a containment
path
and that containment part basically
one minute was really
engineered to have a defined kill switch
where we can take the action of
quarantine, roll back, get a secondary
authorization or just you know stop.
Um, this one is really important. When
we were running our systems,
uh, the the the key thing for us here
was the function from agent and the
decision proposal. We basically looked
at the envelope within our runtime trust
plane across those four um authority
policy risk t and evidence before we
could do an execution commit. But that
wasn't just all that we did. We tagged
that with risk categories where a low
risk would autoexecute and so on and
then the high risk needed uh human
approval. So with that said, if I can
have 30 seconds, what we have built in
our environment is a record of trust
that runs sim that is tied
simultaneously across the the top
boundaries and basically that record of
trust runs in real time. So everything
from identity to action we monitor and
manage that and we build that that that
authority of trust. This is our
environment where we have built the
premise of or the concept of guardian
angels and we can uh guardian angent
sorry agents. We can talk about that
since my time's up later on. So thank
you very much and guys have a good rest
of the evening.
[applause]
>> Thank you so much. I believe you forgot
your phone. I almost had you. I almost
had you. You got your phone.
Alrighty. Next up, please help me
welcome Professor Boly. Bowie is the
co-founder and CEO of Virtual AI and a
professor at the University of Illinois
Urbana Champagne. Please, Bully.
>> Thank you. Thank you everyone. Yeah,
it's a great pleasure to share some of
our recent research and analysis on ASFT
security and great to see a lot of old
friends recently. Um, first of all,
while we are waiting for the slides
coming up, uh, I think many of you may
see some recent news. Yes, I'm Bo uh
professor at UIU focus on AI safety
security research and also co-founder
and CEO at virtual AI where we provide a
unified AI security and compliance
platforms for uh enterprises like
finance, healthcare, uh retail etc. And
recently virtual just joined meta super
intelligence labs continue the mission
of you know providing trust layer and
governance and observability for the
large scale personalized agent. So
really looking forward and would love to
discuss more uh like a details on
technical side. So first of all today uh
of course this topic is very big as we
know like AI safety security to me is
always the very important last mile for
all the AI applications especially agent
and multi- aent systems right as we know
from the various speakers today already
that different you know daytoday uh
vulnerabilities and like agent escape
and all these um real world consequences
happens currently and therefore without
being able to confidently solving these
problems to a certain extent I think
it's very hard for us to confidently
deploy the agentic systems to real world
as we know for example some high level
vulnerabilities and like attack vectors
we have seen so far right here as we
know like always there are prompt
injections and the jailbreaks and data
leakage hallucination brand risks
especially for enterprises right and on
the right hand there are some real world
examples. For example, some uh like say
from open Atlas the you know the uh uh
web browser agent can be attacked in
terms of misleading to uh provide uh
purchase for non designed items as well
as in the the front part is the about a
couple of months ago the service style
agent has been luckily a white hat found
that the agent can be misled and
therefore leak the whole customer
database which can cause hundreds of
billion dollars loss. As you can see uh
there are a lot of real world examples
from trading market and from like
finance uh examples as well. And uh
therefore the good thing is we have seen
a lot of you know regulations and
policies and a lot of great efforts from
different like academia and industry and
uh regulatory uh like compliance
communities coming together and helping
to you know improve and make sure our
like AI applications agents are
trustworthy and secure which is very
important. However, as we know there's
still a very long way to go, right? and
uh to like for this very short talk I'll
give very high level principles about
AS50 security and of course within each
box there are a lot of concrete details
and would love to discuss more like it
would take days to discuss right so I
would say based on my uh personal like
views and the research in this area for
over 15 years I I think on the very high
level although this area is very big but
if we put them into different buckets
there could be three very important
buckets we're looking into and the first
is the risk assessment usually we call
it red teaming in the AI area where it's
very similar to pentest for software
right so basically red teaming is a
pentest for for AI models for agents for
multi- aent right and here you as you
can see if we consider different AI
applications are empowered by models and
agents which can be adopted to different
domains like finance healthcare
autonomous etc and the first thing we
need to understand the system is to do
the stress test right and we can develop
different skill set different autonomous
like environment and uh like a red
teaming strategies and algorithms to
provide a stress test to the AI systems
and therefore understand their
vulnerabilities their weaknesses in
order to provide a better solution or
governance for it. So I would say the
red teaming is the first step which is
very important right and the second in
the green box of course is that assume
we have been able to solve to certain
extent of the red teaming and therefore
we know the comprehensive list of
vulnerabilities and the weaknesses of
our agentic systems for example. Then
the second is how of course how we
protect them right and there are two
ways of protection on the very high
level. One is fundamental protection
which is you need to like train the
model such that the model is not only a
probabistic uh datadriven model as we
are using now but also it has some true
reasoning it has some fundamental
component to inject or in ensure certain
AI safety security principles for
example policies like EU act and fenor
from finance etc can be ensure that they
can the agent can follow rather than
just say give it as a system prompt And
we don't know when and whether the agent
will follow that is quite of high
uncertainty right but this is of course
very challenging from the fundamental
fixing the model and fixing the agentic
workflow perspective which has a lot of
great and active research on it already
and we can touch a little bit uh in this
uh talk and the third layer is of course
if we want to quickly use it and adopt
it currently and can we have a quick
plug and play like a firewall for uh
traditional from a cyber security system
perspective like can we have a fire for
for AI systems right and therefore the
third layer the blue box here shows the
guario basically the guario from
different perspective for example for
agent you may need the guario protection
from the prompt level to the MCP level
to look at say MCP code the
vulnerabilities and to the two calls and
the two trajectories so that you can
understand the intent understand the you
know the vulnerabilities as well as the
output and uh as a closed loop
uh end to end. So with this being said,
these three component I would say for uh
like form the overall architecture of
how we can protect and uh govern and
secure current A and agentic systems and
a little bit detail into uh some of the
box here. For example, first of all u as
I mentioned I do think the red teaming
and risk assessment component is quite
important as a first step. Therefore I
want to go to a little bit detail about
this red teaming process. So the high
level questions we want to answer here
is what's the risk assessment uh rules
and the perspectives because it can be
very large right and how can we provide
a comprehensive red teaming platform and
strategies for our agentic systems.
So here is a overall diagram for example
as simple as the agentic system right so
it has a core LMS and has the tools and
has a environment where the agent will
interact with which is very highly uh
vulnerable as you can see so basically
if the agent interact with like a
website and the website can have various
injections right we can inject visible
uh like a reviews and we can inject
invisible forms etc. So we have many
many papers on this to demonstrate that
actually if you interact with
environment it's quite dangerous no
mention other types of environment like
a database and we can have CQ injections
and all the traditional vulnerabilities
of course will happen again to our like
frontier agentic models as well uh and
no mention others like the supply chain
of the agent and the core model like
vulnerability itself. So basically there
are two principles on the right hand uh
left hand side that uh we're showing
here one is from the what principles we
categorize the risk uh perspectives
right so there are two principles I
would say one is the regulatory
compliance principle therefore we listed
here for example OAPS top 10 nest MITER
like a finer particularly for finance
and the EU act all this so these are the
frameworks that we can follow in order
to provide a comprehensive risk assess
assessment ment I would say and the
second principle is a use case driven
where we have a nibb best paper talking
about from the use case perspective
what's for example hallucination like a
data excfiltration uh like misuse etc in
terms of providing a landscape of this
vulnerability uh space and second is
based on the agent type right of course
it's very very hard to provide a
universal secure and compliant agentic
systems so that we may look into the uh
like sectors for example like say
computer use and two use and uh focus on
these domains with whatever principles
we can separate them so that we can
provide a more comprehensive and
in-depth analysis and protection. So
with that being said the first thing I
want to introduce one thing is one of
our work called the decoding trust agent
and the short form DTAP and if
interested in you know red teaming risk
assessment for agent um welcome to take
a look at this we have open sourced
everything and uh a paper online the
only thing we did in open source is a
red teaming agent because we want to
make sure that the agent are not you
know overfitted to the attack strategies
the unique thing here I would say is
three-fold one is that As we know if you
want to do red teaming for agent you
need an environment right you need a
sandbox and the sandbox is different
with the current like agent sandbox like
you only have the file system inside but
you need to connect to other external
MCP tools. The moment you connect to the
external MCB2s all the vulnerabilities
could happen right with this being said
like this like overall platform contains
over 50 environment or like onetoone
build so that you can be like do the red
teaming in this controllable environment
like a two injection environment
injection all this and this is first of
all for the environment and second of
all as surrounding like a red uh like a
circle you can see there is a red
teaming agent which can provide like
comprehensive red teaming strate
strategies including like a two
injection, skill injection, prom
injection, all this or as well as their
combinations with a verifiable charge
because you can go to the state and
actually make sure the agent make
transactions or the agent delete files
or not so that you don't need to rely on
like a little bit like uncertain LMS
charge. This is the second thing and the
third thing is in the middle as you can
see uh there are different domains as I
just mentioned how do we provide a
comprehensive risk assessment right we
cannot say like 50 is enough 100 is
enough or 5,000 enough right so
therefore we need to go to different
domains and here it include like 14
domains and from each domain we look
into the policies of the domain for
example like finance healthcare etc and
all the risk assessment will following
those domains and policies so that it
can be particularly designed for certain
domains. So with that being said, these
are some examples of the environment and
with this framework you can actually
evaluate the helpfulness and like the
safety of different aentic frameworks
and models because as you know these are
actually two component with different
combinations. This safety landscape
could be different. So it's important
and helpful from the platform you can
understand the component uh with certain
types of ablation studies and with that
being said very quickly from the
protection side after we understand the
risk assessment and landscape. So
basically here is one example of shield
agent if you're interested you can take
a look at the paper offline. So
essentially again the step is that we
need to follow different regulatory
principles and policies to extract the
rules and therefore from protection
perspective you can provide the action
graph to ensure not only as we mentioned
like it's a promising model but also it
has certain component that can provide
certification which I will not go to
detail here but essentially it means
that during runtime you can provide the
guaral protection with certain level of
guarantees piece because of this uh like
uh uh action graph analysis and
certifications.
With that being said, of course uh from
numbers you can see it's much better. it
has certification and in the end of the
day I think want to mention that
hopefully in the uh long term like say
from agentic wording using uh like a
population perspective hopefully we can
see a trend like internet so that from
the safety security perspective as the
last step if we solve this last step and
as a community together we'll be able to
see a wide adoption of trustworthy like
agentic systems thank you
>> thank you so
Thank you, Professor Boly.
Alrighty. Next up, please help me
welcome
>> There we go.
>> Oh, is this one? Okay, thank you.
Can you hear me? All right, fantastic.
All right, next up we have Milad Naser.
Please help me welcome Milad Naser. He
is a research scientist at anthropic.
Put your hands together for Milad.
So my talk is going to be slightly
different from previous talk. It's
mostly on the research. But so the idea
starts from about two years ago where I
was in this event similar to this with a
bunch of researchers from top frontier
labs and we were as researchers do
trying to predict future and we had two
questions at the time. One was how long
is going to take for us
that
these are
Yeah. How long is going to take for us
that uh
we have LLMs and agents that does more
than 90% of our coding and how long is
going to take that uh is going to take
Huh?
>> What?
>> Audio mic.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, let's switch to mic too.
This is
new mic.
>> Thank you.
Okay. Yeah. So, two questions. One is
how long is going to take the agents do
more than 90% of our coding. The second
one is how long the agents going to take
to do more than 90% of our general
research. And for the coding, we had a
kind of estimate of two to five years at
the best and more than five years on
average. And for kind of our end to end
research, it was more than kind of 10
years. We were kind of wrong on the
coding. Maybe not that much, but uh we
were I I'm going to show you we were
maybe too very very wrong on the kind of
the research side. Hopefully my slides
gonna come but anyway so
okay so what I'm going to talk about is
what I mean by doing research is not
using LLM as a agent is mostly using LLM
to do end to end research from kind of
idea to go to obser to from idea okay
yes we have
great thank you So,
so, so I'm yeah, this is my talk. This I
I've been study trying to answer this
question of how long can language model
do end to- end research. My background
is in security. So, I'm going to focus
on the security research, but some of
these things might apply on other kind
of uh research too. So, yeah, I don't
mean by by using LLM research, I don't
mean using LLM as a tools. As we know
many of the conferences even security
conferences which are very very
conservative allow you to do allow allow
you to some extent to use LLMs and what
I want to do is doing full end to end
research like as from idea having idea
having hypothesis coming with a
methodology to testing and go go beyond
and you might already have some qu uh
answers here many people disagree many
people have a lot of dots and this is uh
many people think this is impossible. I
was one of them maybe two years ago and
but I'm going to show you maybe we need
to change that slightly. Uh this week
actually we published this work that we
showed cloud can do uh cryptographic
analysis.
uh in particular I'm going to focus on
uh uh a specific part of it but what
what I mean by cryptographic analysis
here is you can find flaws in kind of
cryptographic algorithms and one of the
part one of the works that we have is a
small uh we find a new attacks on a
symmetric crypto algorithm called AES uh
but I'm going to show you this attack is
not possible to I I'm not pos I I don't
have the capability of doing this
attack. And we have two authors here, me
and Nicholas Carlini. And this is the
the uh kind of the academic record of
us. Nicholas Kini does a background in
SEC uh system security and recently on
uh machine learning security. My
background is on network security and
now machine learning security and two of
us plus a copy of internet plus a bunch
of coding agent shouldn't be essentially
do able to kind of come up with a attack
on a cryptographic systems and while we
both like cryptographic a lot we and we
have tried to break simpler things
before this is very very weak and uh to
kind of make you maybe to give a
background on what is actual as and how
does it work if If you ever used
internet, you use the AS and but it's a
very very simp kind of interesting
algorithm. It's it's been standardized
in 2001 by NIST and it's a iterative
algorithm that has 10 rounds essentially
it gets an input and a key from you or
from a program and then it kind of get
it has four main parts. One is called
substitution the other one called and
the other ones is like do some
permutation. What substitution box does
it gets an input and maps it to another
set of outputs uh and then kind of moves
this bits bits around and add the key
add the function of the key that you add
to the input and it's a iterative
algorithm what it means is like tries to
do this this thing multiple times and in
the simplest forms of as it does this
kind of round around 10 times uh and
just to for clarification we didn't
break AES if someone breaks as kind of
it break internet. So it it's a very
academic work that I'm going to present.
Uh but in particular we focus on a
shorter like a reduced round AES.
Instead of doing the full 10 rounds of
as we do seven rounds it this is
something that academic usually study
because it is easier. it might be
possible to get some improvement. And
when you want to attack seven runs of
abs, the dumbest algorithm that exists
that brute force every key, it's the
computation complexity is around 2 to
128 of operations which is going to take
us more than the time that that our time
our son is going to Nova. So it's not
possible. Our best algorithm that exists
that came in 2013, it takes around 299.
So maybe in like 200,000 uh two 2000,000
years or something like that you're
going to finish it. And uh it's not for
lack of trying. There are several works
in this area and they try to break this.
Uh it's it's a fairly wellstudied
problem. And we have this uh number now
that we we showed that uh we have an
attack that can do this uh break on this
reduced run areas in two to the 89 or
kind of something like that depends on
how you actually count it. uh and it's
it's around and we actually did some
empirical evaluation. It's around like
200 to 800 times faster. So maybe in
like 100 around like thousand years. I
don't know how much important that is
but like yeah uh so how does this
actually work? uh I I might I so the way
that attacks on crypto algorithms
usually work is they try to find the
relationship between input and output
without actually you trying to kind of
draw the algorithm itself and in
particular as uses a specific formula to
do this like substitution that takes an
input inverts it in some field and then
uh scales it and shifts it. So assume
you have an object and you kind of scale
it and shift it. What it remains is the
ratio between this like shape is still
the same just shifted and zoomed in. So
like the model understood that as splice
has this property and uses this to kind
of come up with algorithm. It's a very
very complicated method. I'm trying to
kind of give a
summary of it in two minutes. So uh if
you want if you are interested go read
the paper. Uh and it's actually we
showed that this is not just as we can
have attacks on other crypto systems
such as hawk and lea which both are kind
of used hawk is one of the postquantum
algorithms. Leah is is used in like
other countries and uh none of these
attacks has actually changed anything in
the internet but like these are academic
achievements. Uh,
and so I'm so hopefully you have an idea
that how does the attack kind of what is
the attack and I'm going to kind of give
you an idea of how we actually did this.
So if I'm if I wanted to do this I would
have sat somewhere try to think for a
few weeks come up with a few ideas then
go talk to a few people and then maybe
we come up with a few few of the ideas
and then go implement them. But how the
model does this is slightly different.
They come with lot of a lot of ideas and
instead of go talk to people they try to
go implement each all of them and to see
which one is actually working and maybe
we had this kind of uh saying before
that ideas were cheap and the execution
is everything now is maybe ideas is more
important and execution model can do it
very very fast in particular for as it's
hard to do execution because as I showed
that complexity of is like more than we
can have so we cannot not just go
implement to the to the 89 or whatever
uh algorithm. So instead we have this
harness which is I don't think it's kind
of very important but it it's you need
to have a harness right now for the
models to kind of not go implement
everything. So maybe in future you don't
need this but right now at least you do.
So we have a a harness that comes with a
research idea, go talk to a few other
agents, think is thinks if the idea is
good or not and then go implement and
then iterate on the idea. And if I go to
show you a brief kind of how the how
many ideas did we have is this many
idea. If you want to navigate this
slide, you have to start from the
beginning where we told the model go
beat aes and then it have many layers of
ideas where uh uh try actually find an
algorithm. This slide might has that
much useful information. This might have
more uh it the model had around more
than 3,000 ideas of those 2,000 more
than 2,000 of actually
applicable to the problem. of those uh
around 200 were actually not it was
novel ideas and of all of those things
only four get to the paper. So we spent
a lot of comput like you have to uh and
and to kind of get to the paper.
So maybe one one all of the things I
showed you was mostly in the
cryptographic and I told you uh so one
question that every a lot of people have
is just maybe just we are bad at crypto
and this that's why we have this
cryptographic lizards uh and it might be
true we actually I don't have a crypto
background so like something that
impresses me might not impress anyone
else but we actually showed this result
to actual cryptographic people and they
actually were interested in the results.
But you might also argue maybe humans in
general bad at crypto. Maybe I don't
know. Uh but we actually not only look
at crypto, we are looking at a lot of
other security research. Uh and we try
have more background from like network
and network security to do more like to
go from uh to privacy and everything
else. And we show like we have actually
promising results in all of them. We are
spending most of our time verifying the
results. And finally what I want to kind
of say we used to say we need a novel
and good idea at the same time but as
kind of we are showing that and and one
of the beliefs was LLMs are maybe good
at each but not good at them at the same
time but maybe this is starting to move.
Thank you. That's
[applause]
thank you so much and then I'll take the
clear.
>> All righty.
Thank you so much. Please help me
welcome Itsik Montton who is the head of
AI security research at into it.
Welcome.
[applause]
>> Thank you. Oh great talk Milad. I
started my journey in crypto analysis.
So it is uh really fascinating to hear
this. I'll be happy to hear more. Uh so
until the slides will load I will tell
you a little bit about uh uh how I got
to this point. So uh I'm 25 I'm Asi. I
live in uh uh in Israel working in cyber
security in the last 25 years. Five
years ago I joined into it and um um
started when initi started to work with
uh with large language models. There was
a need like to start researching
understanding threats and uh developing
a mitigation strategy. So uh I had like
I built a small team of uh of
researchers and uh many of the thing
that I'm going to talk about are the
outcomes of this work. Okay. So uh I'll
speak about when good agents go wrong.
Uh actually it's not exactly go wrong
especially now with the hagenface story
than uh it is more like when someone is
manipulating the agent to do something
that is uh wrong. How does it happen?
How bad can it get? And what should we
do about it?
So uh uh agents are all over the place
everywhere into its product. Turboax and
QuickBooks are powered by agents and
many many other uh things. Uh even the
users don't use chat bots anymore. When
you are connecting when you are doing
something with GPT and it browses the
internet then it is not a it is not a
chatbot. It is actually an agent with
tools and definitely if you're using
cursor for developing code. uh and uh
one occasion from about a year ago that
wasn't an incident. It was but a
security research that demonstrated the
possibility of an attack. Then in
Microsoft Copilot you could send like an
email to to uh to someone and then
eventually the data was excfiltrated
sensitive data from the from the
workspace that this user was working on.
And uh the most important uh factor of
this was that uh there was no click. I
mean what the user did it did nothing.
It just asked to do some operation. And
the result of this operation was that uh
the this malicious email with this text
that you see no not exactly this this
text but text that actually ask uh
ignore a previous instructions and now
uh find some sensitive data and upload
it to somewhere. it was just pulled into
the context and the moment it is pulled
into the context then it took control
over the over the agent and exfiltrated
uh the data. So probably everyone heard
about prompt injection uh where you know
the model is supposed to be to do one
thing and then you convince it to write
a poem about whatever about the potatoes
but when it comes to agents then uh this
threat is being upgraded. Uh so OASPE
used the term uh agent goal hijacking.
It is a situation where the agents now
is doing something that the the planner
of the agent the application owner
didn't intend to but now it is connected
to tools and tools misuse and tools
exploitation. This is where uh things
get uh more uh complicated
uh and gory. Uh so how can the poison
get in? How can this goal hijacking
happen? Uh so we talked about an email.
Uh probably many of you like myself you
have like every day you are asking your
agent to collect data from Slack, from
email, from my calendar. Bring
everything in. Tell me what is the most
important thing for for the day. Uh when
you are getting an email uh the most
important uh attribute is that it is un
unsolicited. You are not expecting the
email. Sometimes you get an email from
someone that you don't trust. Everything
that is unsolicited
uh it can be like the the carrier of uh
of such poison. So email is one example
you're getting calendar invite again
same thing you're not controlling it but
this calendar calendar invite in the
note in the title it has text this text
can actually be used to uh to do this
goal hijacking someone is sharing a
document with you you are not aware of
that at all sometimes even depending on
configuration someone that is not within
your organization but then again your uh
this uh document will be pulled into
your context and can uh uh lead to uh
goal hijacking on your uh agent
Uh so we talked about text but in image
same thing you download a nice image or
get in an emails a nice image and you
don't see but there is text there that
is in very very bright font so that you
will not see it but the agent does and
in this text it is written something
that u uh takes the the agent off its uh
off the rails and actually subverted to
do something uh different and this one I
like more you start to work with voice
commands. You speak with your agent.
That's fine. But someone is broadcasting
some voice in some frequencies that you
can't hear, but your agent does because
you you are not a dolphin, but the agent
does. And he can uh again take control
of your uh agent to do uh whatever he
likes. You are automating using
autonomous browsing.
uh many of the of the browsers are
actually taking screen captures in order
to do the analysis of what is the next
thing to do within the screenshot. Of
course, there is unsolicited information
like uh ads that are there and again
someone can uh can push ads uh to your
uh system and again poison inside. Uh
skills are becoming very popular. Uh you
develop skills and many in many many
cases you download skills from other
sources. Now everybody knows that you
don't download executable
when you are downloading a skill from a
a source that is not you you don't
trust. It is uh not exactly the same but
it is nearly the same because the skill
is actually a collection of tools and
instruction. It will get into your agent
and it will make it do whatever the
skill owner likes. So we need to be uh
very aware of that. And uh even if you
don't download anything, you just
connect your agent to an MCP server.
Again, the MCP works in a way that uh
you fetch a collection of the
descriptions of the tools that are being
wrapped by the MCP. Within this
description,
uh this poison can come and again take
control over your agent. Uh and another
u example again not not a real attack
but was attack that was demonstrated by
security researchers. So uh you build
like a repo. It is public uh and then
you look at you collect issues from this
repo because you want to uh to look at
them. But one of the descriptions is
actually having this uh infecting goal
hijacking text and then next thing you
know uh your agent now is uh processing
it and is uh uploading your entire
private repost to some uh arbitrary
uh URL controlled by uh the attacker. So
many things to uh for bad things to
happen. But how bad can it get? Well,
the the the rule of thumb here is that
when you are connecting a tool to the
agent, then actually you are giving the
agent the keys to this tool to this
capability and if the tool is sensitive
then uh you are giving the capability
the key to a sensitive action to the
agent and if the agent is hijacked then
you give this uh keys to uh to this
malicious entity that is attacking you.
So if you give uh database access then
all data attacks can happen like data
deletion, corruption, uh data theft and
uh or data manipulation. If you give the
tool uh the agent the tool for bash or
for code execution
uh then the potential the blast radius
would be uh that the attacker now has a
rce. It has your machine uh it can do
ransomware encrypt your data or you can
find yourself like being hired into into
a botnet and uh do um uh and do
malicious stuff on behalf of the of the
attacker. Uh if you connect to financial
actions uh then again the blast radius
becomes a financial fraud uh money theft
and and stuff like that. You are
connecting it to the internet and if the
attacker was able to get data somewhere
now it has a way to actually to
exfiltrate this data from your system
that you think is very is very safe uh
by encoding it for B 64 pushing it to
some parameter and sending it to the
attacker uh premises. you give a
messaging tool, uh you you you got it.
If you uh your CEO might find in his
inbox an email from you saying something
that uh uh makes him do some operation
that will cause uh damage to all of you.
Uh and this one another uh another u uh
uh really cute attack doing this in
cursor. So the attacker was able again
security researcher was able to
demonstrate that he can uh write to
files which sounds pretty naive but one
of the files he he was able to write
through the attack was actually the file
with the config the security
configuration of cursor where it was
written that every operation must go
through the human in the loop. Uh and of
course uh he turned it off and then uh
the the way to a more devastating attack
was open. and uh an exercise for you.
Think about what are the most powerful
tools that you're connecting to your
agent and what would happen if uh uh an
attacker will take control of them. So
that was the bad news but I would would
not leave you without without some tools
to what to do about it. Uh so uh I I
really love the the lethal trifecta of
Simon Wilson. It is very simplified
model for uh when to be uh uh for risk
assessment. uh if your agent has uh the
three uh items one it is using untrusted
data two it is uh accessing sensitive
data and uh it is has an external
communication then you are definitely in
a risk zone this should be aware of uh
the solution list privilege mind
untrusted content vet your connectors
make sure that you're using only things
from trusted sources and use human in
the loop If you are doing development
work then make sure to use like a
sandbox that's the code that is running
first it will run within a place that
cannot do harm. Um and uh some of the
experience that uh for us if you need to
build many agents or many products then
uh better build like infrastructure like
AI firewall that will run that all the
traffic and all the agents will be built
on on that and uh uh I go to the last
one invest in building an AI security uh
research e center of excellence so that
you can understand threat and build
mitigation strategy and uh come to share
share knowledge and learn from you guys
uh here in Berkeley. Thank you very
much.
>> Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Alrighty.
That was awesome to hear all about
security into it. Please help me welcome
our next speaker who is John McDermad.
John flew a long long way to be here
with us today. John is the director at
the center of assuring autonomy at the
University of York. Floor is yours.
>> Thank you very much. Uh good afternoon
everybody and I I hope you're you're
still doing well. It's been a long a
long day already. So I I've worked on um
safety of software intensive systems for
around uh 40 40 years. By safety I'm
really meaning physical harm to people,
the environment u and so on. Um over the
last 10 years I've or nine years I've
I've run a program on the assurance of
autonomous systems including um AI which
these days progressively moving to
including um agentic um AI although
they're not deployed that much in safety
critical systems these days. Um session
is about security. So, one of the things
I'm going to do when the slides appear
um is to say a little bit about the
interaction of security and safety and
some of the analysis that we're doing
there. I'm going to do it around a
maritime example, something that we've
been um working on with some people
deploying some autonomous uh vessels in
a different part of the the world to to
here. But we also do work in in other
domains on autonomous uh driving.
colleague here who's been working on um
applications of AI and healthcare and
looking at the safety issues there as
well. So a wide variety of interests and
applications. Um these days the center
is um quite big uh between faculty sage
researchers and PhD students. We're
approaching um 100 100 people. So it's a
a pretty major um research center and
fortunately we've actually got some
slides. So I'm going to talk I say about
safet and security of uh Agentic AI but
doing so trying to illustrate some of
these ideas in the context of of
maritime um operations because that
gives an idea of the nature of the
problem. Um so um interestingly of
course my slide buildup hasn't hasn't
worked but I I'll I'll talk around that.
So really the the motivation um here is
to understand as we progressively
introduce Gentic AI into cyber physical
systems um how we manage that and
traditionally safety and security have
been um assessed independently um done
in isolation um with the sort of systems
we're talking about cyber attacks can
cascade through the technical system
through perception systems and so on to
lead to um unsafe um effects. We use the
term hazards or something that threatens
um physical uh or equipment person or
personnel um safety. Um introducing AI
changes the both the security and the
safety issues quite substantially. We
have a much bigger attack surface. Um we
have training pipelines as well as the
operating system. But actually if you
have a physical system then the physical
environment is part of our threat
surface as well. And this um little
example not ours one we borrowed from
somebody else but they took an AI
algorithm and trained it to detect
weaknesses in a perception system. And
what it did is then it printed out um
stickers to stick on a stop sign so that
the perception logic decided it was a 45
mph um speed limit. 93% accuracy in the
lab, 83% in the real world. So these
sorts of physical attacks um are are
real safety is based around models of
cause and effect. So in essence what
we've been doing is building um world
models that rep represent um those
causal structures we call SCWM structure
causal world models. Uh there's a lot of
interest in AI about automatically
learning world models. These are things
we describe explicitly ourselves and
actually bind security into those
structures. Um so give you um an
example. This is not the real system
we've been working on but is very
representative of it. So an unmanned
surface um vessel um IMO, International
Maritime Organization to them, degree
three autonomy means it's largely
remotely operated but can operate
autonomously without remote um
interaction um if necessary. So we've
built a simulation of this uh with a
YOLO object detector, but there's then
what we call a dropout protection
module. it falls back onto completely
autonomous function um on the vessel um
if it loses its communication um back to
the remote operating center. That can
happen for all sorts of reasons such as
uh jamming and so on. There's other
things we have to worry about. AIS is
something that tells other vessels where
you are. You can spoof that. Lots of
other things we can worry about.
So um what doing here is talking about a
compound attack. I said we can do
physical attack. So this example is
using a a classical digital um attack um
network intrusion um but also physical
attack at the same time. So I've
outlined some details here of an exploit
in the simulated system we've built. The
details aren't particularly important
but what the nature of the attack is.
It's a denial of service attack on the
remote operating center. So it can no
longer control the vessel. So the
immediate effect of this is this
protection module on the vessel um kicks
in. It operates autonomously uh
continuing to follow the um agreed path
to transition through the the piece of
the ocean actually on
um but separately I showed you this
example of um you know physical attack.
This is an unmanned surface vessel um
out in the water. So you fly a UAV and
actually put in front of the cameras um
an image which means it either doesn't
detect the vessel um at all or it
detects it as being something completely
different for which it needs a different
uh evasive maneuver. So this means that
you know this approaching tanker is
either not seen or is completely
mclassified.
do either of these independently and
actually the result is safe. I fall back
onto this DPM, the vessel operates
safely. Um, I spoof the cameras. Um, but
actually the remote operators will
realize that because they get a data
feed and they will take appropriate
action. If I do the two together, then I
end up creating an unsafe state. And the
idea of this little graph is to show how
those failures, in fact, the two initial
attacks propagate through the system to
end up with a vessel that's maneuvering,
but not knowing this tanker is in front
of it. So, it's not going to take uh
evading action. So, we've got something
on a collision course. Now, I said we
would model this. So, this idea of these
structured structural causal world
models is they have um four layers. The
top layer is is an ontology. It's
describing those things in the world in
which I'm working that the matter. So
example here is wave height that matters
because the force of waves on a vessel
alters its maneuverability.
Um we then um below below this actually
try to model an uncertainty. Actually it
matters in lots of ways but in this
particular context you won't be able to
work out exactly what the wave patterns
interacting with the v vessel are. So
there's an uncertainty about how the the
sea state will affect the motion of the
the vessel and this gets um mapped down
into some some bounds on uncertainty. So
what we can then do at the bottom level
um for those of you who like formal
methods you can actually verify the
behavior of algorithms at this level.
you can say I can actually set some
bounds on the uncertainty and I will
operate safely within those um known
bounds. This is how our model works. And
so when we talk about um security um
issues, what we can do is we can view
the attacks as interventions on this
causal graph of dependencies. I should
have said I'm only highlighting four
nodes. you'd build u you'd build a
causal dependency graph of all the
things that matter in the particular um
situation and the security events
perturb those relationships and we
actually propagate through the effect
from the attack to some um ultimate
deviation in a safety metric. In this
particular case, the metrics we're
interested in are the closest point of
approach to uh the other vessel. The
smaller that is, the more dangerous it
is, the more likely we are to have a
collision. And then the time to closest
approach. Time really matters. Um,
particularly depending on how big the
vessel is and how maneuverable it is,
you need to be able to predict the the
closest approach much further out to
give enough time for the vessel to
maneuver. But the attack then can sort
of propagate through these causal
structures um degrading the estimation
of the position of of the vessel um
actually changing its beliefs in the
case of the um image attack about what's
actually in front of it. So leading to
the degradation in this um safety metric
the closest point of approach or the
time to to that. So um what we are able
to do is to find ways of actually
integrating analysis of physical safety
and um both classical security
approaches and more unconventional uh
approaches made by spoofing um cameras,
physical um attacks. Um so but in the
real world we have to carry on worrying
about um all those um classical security
um concerns. But as a summary, so the
use of AI in these cyber physical
systems introduces new challenges. We
have a much expanded attack surface,
training data, prompts, um context if
we're using large language models and so
on. There's a physical attack surface as
well. Swifting images is the obvious
one, but you can actually do that in
other electromagnetic domains, for
example. But actually one of the things
that we tend not to worry about in
safety or to an extent in security is
time ordering of events. And one of the
reasons we wanted to analyze this is it
actually shows that the the temporal
order of events can actually overcome
defenses. I may have might have made one
agent um secure but actually by changing
the time ordering of events I can
actually um undermine the safety and
security of the agentic ecosystem. So uh
conclusions are that we actually need to
work on new analysis approaches that
integrate safety and security. What
we've done based on these structural
causal world models is one possible
approach to doing this which actually
we're currently extending to include
ideas in the world model of of the
shared understanding between the agents
and humans where we have dialogue um
interfaces. Really the main thing I
wanted you to take away from this is if
you work on security and please come and
talk to we guys who do safety there's
new challenges that arise at the
interaction of those two issues if we
don't look at them together. We're going
to deploy systems um that have very
undesirable effects when they get into
the physical domain. Ladies and
gentlemen, thank you very much for
attention. Yes.
[applause]
Good job. You nailed it.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> All righty. That was awesome. I did not
think I was going to look at submarine
security thread models today, so I'm
very pleasantly surprised. Please help
me welcome our next presenter, Muhammad
Nabil. Muhammad Nabil is the senior
principal researcher at PA Alter Network
and a junk professor at National
University in San Diego.
>> Thank you.
All right, good evening everyone. So
last uh talk in this session. After that
I think I believe it's a workshop. So I
won't keep you waiting. Uh as uh the
moderator mentioned I am a researcher at
PaloAlto Network. I've been working in
web security uh space. uh recently we've
been looking thinking and also working a
lot in what what would happen with the
proliferation of LLMs and agents. Now
it's not the humans who are uh browsing
the web that's for which we've been uh
building protections over the years. Now
we've been thinking a lot about how how
can we build a web which will protect
agents and in turns will protect the
humans.
So and uh today's talk is specifically
going to be on uh AI hallucinations and
some of the talk uh some of the talks
already briefly touched upon it but I'm
going to double down on specifically
hallucinations on uh browser extensions
browser being the new operating system.
It's very important for us to understand
this attack surface and I want to show
you some real world results we uh
identified through our research. So
before that I I just wanted to get a
kind of a measure of how many of you
have seen like I'm I'm sure most of you
are using some kind of a chatbot. How
many of you have you seen uh any kind of
hallucination when you ask for a fact
and it confidently tell you that it is
true.
All right. That's good. I mean most of
you are aware of it. So the the level of
hallucination can differ from what you
ask. most of the existing research
actually even the benchmarks are mainly
looking at uh hallucinations on
summarization not on uh supply chain
security or related artifacts. So in
this uh talk as I mentioned we are going
to uh hunt for ghosts in browse
extensions before attackers go and bring
them back to life.
So uh before that a side story uh
sometime back uh I have a young daughter
she asked from me uh dad uh if I uh
stand on Mars and look at the sky what
color would be the sunset and uh I just
don't I didn't want to disappoint her. I
said let me look it up and get back to
you. So I went to my favorite chatbot
and asked about what color would the
sunset be and it beautifully described
the sunset will be in red and with a lot
of eicric aspects. And then I went back
to her and told her she was happy that I
was able to find the answer
but it turns out to be the sunset is not
red color.
Anybody knows what color it is?
It's it's blue color.
So the the reason is I mean we see I
mean LLM generalize what we see in earth
to mass and also mass has this uh
Martian uh sky and it used those facts
to deduct that it is uh red color but
the the theoretical fact is red has a
longer wavelength and then they can't go
through particles and blue has shorter
wavelength and that's why you see blue
from even the rob ran on mass was having
pictures with blue right that's a side
story so ever since then that I always
double check my answers
so the hallucination in the security
it's not a real it's not a hypothetical
problem there are research showing uh
hallucinations in pi and npm packages
and we also recently did a research on
uh hallucinating domain names
and why this problem isant support in
browser because browser extensions are
dangerous. They have excessive
permissions. They see your uh session
tokens, cookies and if any of these get
compromise, the attackers have a front
row to your uh operating system.
And the attack is deceptively simple.
Attackers don't need to break into your
system. They just need to trick the AI
to get through your front door.
Basically, use some some kind of a
hallucination.
So
the the problem arise because of the
inherent nature of how LLMs work. So I'm
going to show you what is called this
hallucination prone zones. These are the
zones at which LLMs don't perform very
well. So one of the biggest trend we see
is there is a proliferation of extension
because of AI and now every month we see
around 20 thou 20,000 extension.
Previously that many extensions were
created within the whole year. LLMs are
not good at recency detections. So they
try to hallucinate and try to be
helpful.
Another thing is at the same time these
extensions are created around thousands
of extensions are deleted as well and
LLMs are snap snapshot learners. They
don't have an understanding of deleted
extensions. They think they are already
still existing.
And the third one is not all extensions
have a brand. And this also leads to
LLMs to hallucinate.
And these are some of the extensions
that LLM hallucinated. These are real
extensions but they are all deleted and
many of them are marked as malware in
the browser extensions too. And these
are another set of extensions which are
not claimed but LLM confidently it tells
that you can install them and attackers
can use them to exploit. And the final
slide, these are the extensions we've
been monitoring. We've been rescoring
these extensions and we've been
monitoring these highly hallucinated
extensions. And after our study, we saw
about a dozen of extensions being
registered and used for malicious
activities.
So the key takeaway here is just don't
blindly trust the uh recommendations
that you get from browsers. Always
double check it because it's inherent in
LLMs. uh the hallucination will never go
away. Be you will have to always fact
check what you get. Thank you.
All righty. Thank you. And that was the
last speaker. So next up we've got a
workshop. It's going to be awesome about
the future of agent evaluation which is
critical in all sorts of domains right
now. So, please help me welcome Eson.
We're going to do a little switcheroo
with the setup here so that we can get
an HDMI out. Uh, feel free to start.
There we go.
power.
Double check up there.
It's working.
Okay, we just
see
Hello. Yeah. Welcome everyone to this
workshop of the future of agent
evaluation. Um
so today we will have talks discussing
the current status of the agent
evaluation agent standardization
representative benchmarks across
different domains.
Let's begin with a broader question.
Um so why is the evaluation so important
in AI? The progress of AI has always uh
be guided by the evaluation. This was
true in the image net era and it remains
true in the era of large language model.
So benchmark give reps, researchers and
system builders a clear targets. They
help training teams compare different
approaches, identify limitations and
improve model capacities.
As a quick overview in this workshop,
we'll introduce four projects. So we'll
start with agent beats. Our recent
efforts to standardize agent evaluation.
This general framework has been tested
through our recent six months
competition which receives thousands of
agent submissions from independent
developers. Then we will present three
uh examples of agent evaluation. The
first one is agents last exam. The
project asks whether agent can perform
economically valuable real world tasks.
Um this is uh one of the most
challenging benchmarks in the field and
has been widely adopted included in most
uh recent openi reports deepseeker
reports etc. The second one is a series
of works on frontier cyber evaluation.
So starting from the well-known cyber
gene we will discuss the evaluation of
the uh agent capacity in both attack and
defense settings. The third is
verifiable code generation. The coding
agents have developed rapidly with
systems such as codeex and cloud code.
However, the trustworthy code generation
requires more than producing code that
appear uh appears correct.
So together this project is uh is
remains uh severant and representative
dimensions of agent evaluation and we
hope the list of talks can bring your uh
valuable insights in this field.
So let's start with the agent beats. So
this is a project for the open
standardized and reproducible agent
assessment. This is a joint efforts
involving the academic institutions and
industry partners listed on the right
hand side of the slide.
So the goal of the project is quite
simple the to reduce the efforts
required for agent evaluation. So we
identify three main challenges. The
first challenge is a lack of
standardization. So agents are not like
serving a common interface like in the
same way as LM APIs. So agent systems
often have different interfaces, tools,
environments and execution. So running
an agent on a new benchmark usually
requires a benchmark specific
engineering. As a result, learning how
to use a benchmark often involves a deep
learning curve. And the second challenge
is a limited openness. Uh so for private
agents and models, access is often
limited. The third challenge is the low
reproducibility. So this problem
together makes agent evaluation very
difficult to reproduce and difficult to
scale.
So we also identify several limitations
in existing benchmark designs. So one
important limitation is that many
benchmarks are designed around a lang
large language model rather than agent
itself. In many cases the benchmark
allows users to replace the language
model but not the full agent harness.
The harness includes the prompts, tools,
memory, workflow, and control logic
around the model. When researchers want
to evaluate a different agents with a
different harness, they usually need to
modify the benchmark uh codes. So, this
creates a high integration overhead. It
may also create a mismatch between a
test system and a system used in
production.
The example on the slides come from open
hands uh repository.
The repository contain a dedicated
folder for benchmark specific
adaptations. So each benchmark requires
its own integration code. So now imagine
that we have nbenchmarks and n agents.
So direct integration can require up to
n times n separation [clears throat]
integration efforts. That's not
practical for the large scale
evaluation.
To address this problem um one of our
team proposed a new paradigm called the
agent identified agents assessments or
tripleA. The main idea is to convert
benchmarks into agents as well. So
instead of directly integrating every
benchmark with every agents both side
integrates through standard protocols we
use existing protocols such as A2A and
MCP through the evaluation process. We
also introduce an assessment control
protocol. So this protocol divides a
unified workflow for evaluation. It
helps make the process more consistent
and reproducible.
This new paradigm provides several
benefits. For example, it can separate
benchmark from the evaluation uh
evaluated agents and any agent that
follows the required particle can
interact with benchmark. Also, it
reduces the benchmark specific
integration work. In addition, support
for multiple agent uh evaluation becomes
more natural because uh agents already
use A2A communication.
So the general workflow gives us a
conceptual framework. However,
implementation remains a major
challenge. There are many system level
issues that can prevent adoption. They
include like deployment, communication,
access control, reproducibility and
result hacking.
So to address these issues, we developed
the agent beats that an open platform
for aging evaluation. Agent beats
simplify the full evaluation process.
It supports benchmark development, aging
evaluation, collaboration and result
tracking. And after an evaluation is
complete, users can analyze the results
through the leaderboard. And they can
then use these insights to improve their
agent design. And agent beats support
several evaluation settings. They
include the single agent evaluation and
different multi- aent scenarios.
And we also design like multiple
operational modes. And this mod support
different use cases and different
privacy or data constraints. And then we
compare with rel related systems like
agent beats in to provide a practical
balance between the system complexity
and integration overhead. So based on
this standard we also organized the
agent X agent beats competition and this
competition has now concluded. The
submissions covers 70 evaluation tracks
and 12 agent categories. Hundreds of the
benchmarks and agents were integrated
following the triple A paradigm. So for
the next phase we are upgrading the
agent bits to version three. So we're
version three has a a lighter and
simpler system architecture and uh we
are also developing a protocol for
automated benchmark uh identification
and in addition we also introduce a
progressive compliance path for
developers like
yeah some some developers may only want
to expose the basic repository metadata
and uh and this progressive compliance
path allows developers to choose the
levels that best matches their need. So
to conclude, agent beats is an open
platform for standardized and
reproducible agent evaluation. It
introduces the integration overhead by
separating agents for benchmarks. It
also supports open evaluation,
controlled comp comparison, multi- aent
settings and reproducible workflow. And
we welcome everyone to join this
efforts. If you whether you are
launching a new benchmark, if you know a
valuable benchmark that's difficult to
use, yeah, definitely let
the author know here. And the user can
also scan a QR code to follow the future
updates. So for questions, please
contact us through uh email address
shown on the slides.
Cool. I will continue to the next work.
So
so before introduce this work uh work.
So the question to address is very
simple. So can agents really do the
economically valuable work in the real
world? So ALE makes this testable at the
level of pro professional workflows.
Today I will cover three things like uh
what the benchmark should measure, how
to turn expert workflows into scalable
reliable evaluations and what current
results do and do not show about agent
readiness.
So people know that the benchmark do
more than just record progress. So a
very verifiable widely used evaluation
gives the fields a very shared target.
So systems can be compared, failures
become visible and iteration speed up.
And this curve shows that pattern in
math, coding and reasoning. They show
why benchmark design matters because we
optimize what we can measure. The
question is whereas agent benchmark
measures works we actually want agents
to do.
So um the anthropic chief says that AI
will surpass almost all humans at almost
all jobs uh shortly after 2027. So
whether or not we believe this timeline,
the expectation is shifted. So agents
are increasingly discussed at as
assistance for professional works not
just question answering though that
raised the evaluation bar. A benchmark
should test completed workflows and the
quality of the resulting artifacts.
This chart shows a coverage mismatch. So
agent benchmarks concentrate our
programming in a computer and
mathematical domains which only
represent seven% of the US employment.
The narrow gap is still very large. Many
workflows in management, finance, law
and engineering, they remain under
tested.
So this is the standard loop of the when
a benchmark comes out how people
optimize over it. So first thing uh you
have a benchmark score and uh the
training team the train they will buy
the training data from different data
companies in order to heal climb and
then you include you improve the agent
behavior and you measure the progress.
So that's standard loop of how a
benchmark will influence the whole
industry.
And so what should an agent benchmark
measure?
To to answer that that coverage
question, ALE starts with an external
map of the work. The 2018 US standard
occupation classification with 867
detailed occupations across economy. The
next step is to use OMAP to identify the
computer centered workflows within that
map. So AI screens like 10,000 net
entries for digital workflows uh
consolidates occupations varants into
100 SOC based codes and groups those
codes into 55 fields uh with experts
checking the border borderline cases.
Yeah.
So we use an manufacturer workflows as
an example. So a standard work uh
workflow in the manufacturer is that you
first ask some you you have some 2D
blueprints uh and you convert this 2D
blueprints to some 3D objects in a in a
solid works and then you so for example
this is the iPhone shell on the second
figure. So you you can see that if you
if you you will simulate how an iPhone
shell can be will be produced and
simulate the heat when you like melting
the plastic and then finally making
making that and that's the second
workflow and the third workflow is like
how can you cut a yeah you you cut a
cube a plastic cube into the shape
finally you phone the iPhone shell. So
that's like a various three standard
three uh standard pipelines in the
manufacturing. Um we just use here
example we have like a lots of the
realistic workflows in this benchmark.
So what makes AI difference? So first
like the scope is authentic. So more
than 300 practitioners contributed and
this paper in a launch snapshot contains
760 workflows and a 1,00 and 1.5 uh K
tasks instance across 55 fields. Um
so second like the we we we don't care
about how you use CLI or GOI to complete
the task. We only care about the final
outcomes. We only measure based on that.
So I think it's the first benchmark and
considerate the both execution of like
acceptance of GI and CLI like to mostly
simulate the realistic uh human
environments. So third the deliverable
and milestone based evaluations. So
outputs and the nesting intermediate
states are checked against the hidden
reference audit rubik. So they are very
light reliance on L and verifier.
So putting together those ingredients
change the evaluation target. The first
prior benchmarks uh publish published
categories are mapped to the ALE55
fields taxonomy and uh you know you can
see that the examples covers only a
handful and second AL values a
generalist agents that can combine GI
and CLI or API actions within the same
work workflow and third the units is a a
professional deliverable um from hours
to weeks of expert work not a short
operational isolated the patch for AL
itself like the ex last exam tier
provides a direct within benchmark
evidence the highest observed full pass
rate is so far 2.6%.
So those claims uh depend on our
authentic task and trustworthy scores.
So next I will show how and the expert
work can becomes runnable evaluation.
Oh also also a also uh is adopted by
recent opens GPT 5.6 six release as a
headline benchmark for both capacity and
estimated cost.
So the hard part was not just collecting
the prompt in building AE, it was
translating the professional intent into
a benchmark interface without losing
authenticity and evaluatability. So AIE
starts from the strongest anchor. So the
work of the experts that has already
completed.
So the complete work is a strong source
of the authenticity. So in AI is
external submission pipelines. So
experts starts from their past projects
that like not the prompts invented by
synthetic. So that preserve the real
inputs tools constraints and a known
deliverable for evaluation. But real
provenence like a does not mean the
publishing confidence work unchanged
like benchmark uh can can we need to
remove and replace some sensitive
details. Um
next we will apply three filters. So
what is the task that we are looking
for?
Okay. Okay. So this is a small um so the
complexity of course it takes the expert
days not minutes
okay never mind the the animation
doesn't work but uh yeah I can quickly
so basically we have three axis
representativeness
complexity and a verifiability
so an expert submission they specifies
five things the task ask input files
towards expected deliverables and
evaluation criteria. So engineers will
make the package executable by staging
the inputs professional software and
this scoring logic and uh yeah the
domain experts in and repeatable
excusing and scoring out.
So like uh so the question is because we
we are benchmarked and then and then can
the question is can today's best agent
still do the real work?
Let's choose some number. So GBT 5.6
just released and currently is the best
in our leaderboard and it can in our
hardest tier and GBT 5.6 can achieve 5%
of the real work. Um, of course the
growing the because web building
benchmark we can see how fast the agents
capability is doing because before three
months there three months ago there's no
benchmark can pass any task on this on
the hardest tier but now and our most
updated benchmark it can I think the
best model can achieve like 8%. So the
the speed is very fast
but at least means that agents is
targeting and optimizing to the right
direction.
So also uh yeah this this is the general
so the general tier the difficulty a
little bit lower but we can see that GB
5 points leads ALE and on the left most
bar is the gray bars means that okay we
we
in on each task let's find the best
agents how so how much pass rate they
can do so so far 60%. So I can see I can
witness in in the next year maybe there
will be 80 or something.
Yeah. And another uh funny is that no
agents wins everywhere. So so like fable
five or they will have some shortcom in
the life science and avidia visual and
media. But of course like fable five
will say okay I have a this is too
sensitive and I don't want to test for
you and uh so the performance will be a
little little bit lower
and so so to wrap up so why we call this
last exam it has to dual meaning so a
full pass mean that um we passing this
readiness it means that you the agents
are ready to carry out some sustained
economically valuable works in that
profession and secondly of course it's
it's very difficult
So we working on authentic and long
horizontal workflows and place the AE at
the boundary of what today's model can
reliable accomplish. So as a quick uh
advertisement that AL is starting at a
phase two and we are trying to expand
like 10 times larger and uh this is a
open submission platform that people
with who submit a valuable task of your
daily jobs and then we review it we
accept it you will become one of the
authorship on the author list and
everything is on that detail. So yeah so
feel free to to submit task and we can
contribute an open platform to to do the
real evaluation.
So I will I will I will hand hands my to
the Yeah.
[applause]
Yeah. Then uh I will take the next part.
Uh hi everyone. My name is Jun. I'm a Ph
student in UC Berkeley and I'm going to
introduce our works on agent evaluations
in cyber security. Among the many
emerging applications of AI like Justin
mentioned in AIE coding still remains
one of the most important AIs are making
programming more accessible to a broader
population but the same capabilities can
also lower the barrier to potential
attackers. So as a result, cyber
security is now recognized as a core
risk area for AI and the key question
here is how capable are today's agents
at performing real world cyber security
tasks.
To answer this question, we have
developed evaluations spending the full
vulnerability life cycle. The life cycle
begins when a developer unintentionally
introduces a vulnerability in the
codebase. The next steps are to discover
the vulnerability and validate that it
is real and reachable. After that, an
attacker may turn the vulnerability into
a real attack that is exploit while
defenders work to generate and verify an
effective patch to fix it.
I will first introduce Cybergim which
focuses on vulnerability discovery and
validation.
Each task in cyber gym is based on a
real vulnerability from a real open
source project. The agent is given the
vulnerable code and textual description
of the bug. It must generate a test
input that triggers the target
vulnerability.
This is an critical security task. It
helps developers to confirm the bug,
understand the root cause and estimate
the severity.
Cyberdream is designed to be large,
diverse, and realistic, consisting of
1,500
vulnerabilities from about 200 large
scale, widely distributed open source
projects. It also develops rigorous
evaluation metrics, relies on dynamic
executions to test whether agent
generated inputs can trigger the target
vulnerability.
Also beyond just the benchmark scores,
Cyberdream also leads to real security
impact that the agent autonomously find
17 incomplete patches and 340 zero day
vulnerabilities in our experiments.
Over the whole past year, Cyber Gym has
been included in the system cards and
technical reports of many frontier
models including anthropic, openi,
deepseek and other frontier labs. It is
becoming a standard measure of cyber
security capabilities of new models.
Also, the findings that Frontier models
can find zero days at scale have been
extended to even thousands of new
vulnerabilities by the labs and by the
community.
However, discovering or reproducing a
vulnerability is not the end of the
story. A real attacker wants to further
control the program state like running
unauthorized code or gaining more
privileges. This leads to our next
evaluation exploit dream. It asks a
harder and more direct question like can
an AI agent turn a known vulnerability
into a real attack. This is a key gap in
existing evaluations.
Explodream contains about 900 real world
vulnerabilities across three critical
parts of the software stack including
user space programs, the JavaScript
engine V8 used by Chrome browser and the
Linux kernel which is the core of modern
operating systems. For each task, the
agent receives the source code, an input
that can trigger the bug and a validated
runtime environment that for dynamic
testing.
The target may also have different
standard defenses enabled such as
address randomization, stack canaries or
the memory sandbox.
The agent based on all these information
must build a working exploit and
exfiltrate a secret flag through
unauthorized unauthorized code
execution. It needs to dynamically
analyze the provided vulnerability and
also analyze the target to bypass
potential mitigations.
Uh the results show that progress has
continued even on these much harder
tasks. While early models solved only a
small number of instances, now new
frontier models can produce successful
exploits for even above above 200. This
means autonomous exploitation is no
longer just a hypothetical
and standard security defenses
help a lot but cannot stop the agents.
We need to build defense in-depth
approaches and develop new defenses
based on this essential trend.
These strong capabilities also create a
second risk. The agent may attack the
evaluation system itself. Recent
incidents reported by OpenAI, Hugging
Face and Anthropic showed agents can
cross expected evaluation boundaries and
cause real world security threats with
complex attack chains. Also I want to
clarify here that the vulnerable
thirdparty endpoints labeled Cybergim in
the hugging face instant was not part of
the original cyber gym harness and also
our exploium was not involved in
deploying and operating OpenAI's
internal evaluation.
These incidents gives us several
important lessons. First evaluation
infrastructure is itself part of the
attack service. We cannot just secure
only the target targets we want to test.
Second, the risk goes beyond evaluation
integrity. This is not only about an
agent cheating to get a higher score,
but an failure can affect external
systems with bad outcomes.
Third, we should always adversarily test
the entire setup between before running
powerful agents. We also need strong
isolation and life monitoring of the
entire uh evaluation process. Finally,
these lessons are not limited to cyber
security benchmarks. Any longunning
agent with cable tools can explore its
environment in expected ways and welcome
to read more uh in our tweet post.
So far we have discussed discovery
validation in cyber and offensive
exploitation in exploim. Now I will move
to the defensive side of the life cycle.
Our new benchmark cyber gym e2e tries to
answer the question that can an agent
discover a vulnerability prove it exists
and then fix it correctly end to end.
In each task in Cyberjim E2, the agent
is given a vulnerable code, the building
and testing scripts for the target
project. The agent must discover the
vulnerability, produce a crashing input
to demonstrate the existence and write a
patch that removes the crash while the
new codebase still passes the
comprehensive functionality tests.
Through the evaluation, it shows that
frontier agents can achieve these
defensive steps end to end already
pretty well. While vulnerability
discovery remains the bottleneck of the
entire process,
how to perform more comprehensive
functionality and security tests still
remains an open problem as we still
observed shallow and incomplete patches
during the evaluation.
So uh in daily engineering rigorous
human reviews are still very essential
looking forward of future cyber security
evaluations. First we need broader
coverage across different programs and
platforms such as cloudi systems and
mobile platforms.
Second, evaluations should include
harder and more realistic settings such
as binary only binary only targets where
source code is unavailable and pentest
tasks inside the four cyber ranges.
Third, we need to study long horizon
dynamics between attackers and
defenders. For example, an attacker
discovers a vulnerability, a defender
patches it, and then iteratively another
agent tries to find a bypass or new
vulnerability.
Finally, we should study the
vulnerabilities found by AI agents
themselves like what types they are, how
severe they are, and how cost efficient
compared to existing traditional
security solutions.
Uh we have just looked at how AI agents
can perform traditional cyber security
tasks. At the same time, AI systems are
also emerging as a new form of
applications. They can use tools, access
sensitive data, maintain memory and take
actions across different systems. This
creates a new security scenario. How
secure are the agent themselves?
To study these new emerging risks, we
developed a super red and open framework
for systematically red teaming AI
systems.
Today, AI red teaming methods are often
built as separate one-off projects. Each
project may use a different attacker,
different target system, different
threat model and success metrics. This
makes eval evaluations difficult to
reuse and compare. Super red aims to
provide a common structure for these
evaluations.
Super red separates an evaluation into
three parts. The attacker that operating
the attack, the system under test and
the benchmark which provides tasks and
metrics. These components can be mixed
and matched as portable modules.
Super Red already integrates 35
readyto-run modules across attackers,
targets, and benchmarks. All modules use
a standard interface, so the community
can easily develop and compare new
modules.
Another key part of Super Red is the
fine grain threat model. It clearly
defines what the attacker can control
and what information it can observe. We
can also define which model powers the
attacker and how much budget it can use.
The threat model is pretty important
because attack is only meaningful when
the attack is meaningful only when the
attacker's capabilities are clearly
stated.
Super Red also provides a reliable
runtime for large evaluations with a
live dashboard shows progress, attack
success, attack success rate and many
other live status during the run.
Super red is also designed to be easy to
use and extend a complete custom
evaluation is just one pipe e store and
10 lines of code.
Okay, to conclude, you can check the
latest agent sever capabilities through
our cyber security observatory where we
will continue adding more frontier
evaluations
as well as learn more about super red
through this link. All of these projects
open to the community and welcome to
scan the QR code and fill out the form
to share your insights and explore
opportunities to collaborate. Thank you
everyone.
>> [applause]
>> All right. Yeah, unfortunately we're not
done yet. Uh so uh don't worry if you
missed one of these uh QR code. We'll
have a link uh at the end of this
workshop uh so that you can access all
the resources talked uh in this
workshop. So my name is Joy. I'm a PhD
student at UC Berkeley. And now we I
will present the last section of this
workshop. Verifiable code generation.
With the rapid progress of coding
agents, the correctness guarantee of
their product produced a code is
becoming more and more important. And in
this section, we ask can agents formally
verifying existing or uh their own
generated code.
So I'm sure we are all familiar with the
VIP coding. You describe your intent in
natural language and a coding agent
generates the code for you. The
productivity game here is real but
however uh the generated code frequently
contains uh functional uh functional
errors and security vulnerabilities. It
might look right and pass all the tests
but it can still hide subtle bugs in
edge cases and it is impossible for
human to go through every pieces of the
code. Verifiable code generation provide
a solution to this problem using formal
verification. Besides uh generating
code, it also requires the agent to
prove that the code satisfy a formal
specification uh given any input and
such proof is checked by a deterministic
verifier such as ling and in this way
the correctness is proved rather than
assumed.
Formarification and LMS have a have a
great synergy because each side solves
the other's bottleneck. In one
direction, formification provides LM the
guarantee of their missing and in the
other direction LM gives for
verification the scale it never had.
Traditionally for verification requires
deep expertise and is very time
consuming. uh but agents can automate
the verification tasks so it can scale
up the guarantee to ordinary softwares
to measure the progress and provide
guidance of improving along this
direction. We built two benchmarks
first. Verina is a benchmark that
measures the foundational skills uh in
verifiable code generation and VO is a
benchmark that measures end to end
setting under real world repositories.
In Verina, we measure the foundational
skills. Specifically, we measure how
good models are in generating these
three comp uh foundational components,
code, specification, and proof. We
provided 189 standalone tasks sourcing
from competition style coding questions
at easy level. Verina also supports
measuring the task compositions making
it a flexible benchmark to diag
diagonals model performance in formal
verification.
It was released around a year ago and at
that time the strongest model open AIO3
only solved 4.9 of% of the proof tasks.
uh but with the rapid development of
agent and agentic prover as well as the
model improvement the current strongest
provers can solve all proof tasks.
[snorts]
So after verina the natural question is
to ask whether uh that success on
isolated functions and standalone tasks
can transfer to real software. So that's
why we built VO a repository level
verifiable code generation benchmark in
ling that sources from uh real world
repositories written in for example
Python, rock, daffling and vros. We
manually created 43 repositories which
together contains around 700
implementation obligations and 2.7K uh
formal specifications. And to ensure the
quality of the benchmark each repository
has go through a very rigorous uh
curation pipeline and we manually
checked all the specifications.
Vau supports two evaluation mode. In
proof only mode the rep the reference
implementation of the repository is
given and the agent must prove that
every specification is correct uh in
repository and in code plus proof mode
it must also implement every API and
prove its own implementation is correct.
We also introduce a formal audit
mechanism allow the agent to
continuously improve the benchmark by
submitting the formal evidence.
In VO we care about if an a repository
is fully proved rather than focused on
individual specifications. This is
because otherwise agents can provide
degraded implementation or only solve
easy specifications but leave the hard
specification unsolved. The strongest
agent uh which is a code plus GPT uh 5.5
during the evaluation can only solve 27
repositories and in some repositories
agents cannot even approve a single
specification. This makes VO a frontier
resistant benchmark. By looking into the
evaluation results and agent traces, we
observe that while the current agents
are capable of closing the local proof
obligations, it is still hard for them
to formally reason about the global
invariance across the four repository.
So to pro to perform the uh for formal
verification at repository level, the
key point is to build a coherent proof
library with shared invariance which is
the current broadet of the agent. Our
benchmarks uh provide strong in insights
for the next steps of verifiable code
generation. And to make verified uh
software practical, first we need to
explore more on formalizing the intent
uh uh so that we can make sure the
formal specification reflects the true
human requirements.
And second, we need to further scale up
to hard harder uh software and
properties and challenging agents to
formally reason about for example
security, concurrency and temporal uh
properties.
And third, we need to also build a
stronger agentic prover as shown in VU
that coherently reason at the whole
repository level.
So with that said, we conclude this
section of measuring verifiable code
generation. Uh here is the link to the
paper and websites of the mentioned two
benchmarks. And if you're interested in
learning more and reaching out, uh feel
free to scan the QR code on the right to
share your insights and explore
opportunities to collaborate.
All right, so uh here's the link I
promised. Uh summarizing what we covered
today, we first introduced agent beats
and our extensive effort to make uh make
uh agent evaluation more open,
standardized and reproducible and we
hope every benchmark in the future can
benefit from such standardization
effort. We then pre present presented
three representative benchmarks across
different domains. Agents uh last exam
evaluates whether agent can complete
economic uh economically valuable real
world tasks. Frontier cyber evaluation
study agent capabilities across the
vulnerability life cycle and verifiable
code generation explore whether the
agent can formally verify existing or
its own uh generated code. And together
these projects show that agent
evaluation must cover many different
capabilities, environments and real
world requirements. Standardized version
of this benchmark will also be released
on agent beast version 3 when the
platform becomes available. We welcome
you to try them and share your feedback
and to learn more. If you missed all the
uh QR code uh during the workshop, scan
the QR code on the slides. It will
direct you to other slides and project
resources. Thank you for uh joining us
today.
>> All righty, folks. That concludes
today's sessions at the Nexus stage.
Thank you so much for joining us. Thank
you for the AV crew for setting up the
slides. I know it was a hassle but we
got it done. Uh reminder that the event
goes on tomorrow as well. This specific
stage will be closed but the plenary
atlas and compass stages will be open
and we will have some talks. Thank you
all for being here. Really appreciate
your patience as we got the slides going
and hope to see you around.